当我坐在一个人的对面,我很少能
I've rarely sat down across  from somebody
从他们口中表达出听出他们到底想要什么
and had them be able to articulate what do you acutally want
他们没办法回答这个问题
They cannot answer that question
他们用瘾,爱好,想分泌更多的多巴胺来当答案.
and they fill it with additions ,they fill it with hobbies,they fill it with dopamine chase.
他们用太多的东西当答案,却没人能真正的回答那个问题.他到底想要什么?
They fill it with so much stuff and nobody can answer that question.What do you want?
他们到是能回答出他们不想要什么.
为什么他们自己会感觉到难受,是因为他们,他和她.
It's what i dont want and why am i feeling  this uncomfortable.It's cos of them,It's cos of him,It's cos of her.
你想要的东西并不会自主出现,除非你开始追求它.
你并不会追求它,除非你自己知道自己想要什么.
Nothing  that you want will manifest itself unless you aim for it and you won't aim for it unless you know what it is.
你不知道你想要什么直到你问自己这个问题
You won't know what it is unless you ask yourself
你会问自己为什么自己从来没有问过自己这个问题呢?
也许答案是从来没有人给你解答这个问题到你需要的程度.
光这个没有跟你解答问题到你需要的程度的事实,这就已经是一个很严肃的问题了
and then you might say well why don't you ask yourself and the answer is well maybe no one ever explained to you that you needed to which is a crucial issue and
也许自己本身就不信任自己.你会想如果我让我自己知道我到底想要什么
and maybe you dont also trust yourself.Because you might think if i let myself know what i wanted.
从过往经验来看,我为了失败可谓是做了一切的功夫.
所以我宁愿让我自己对本身不清不楚,这样我才不会让自己在重要的事上失败.
Given  my bloody track record,i would do everything i could to screw it up.So i'll just keep myself opqque to myself sothat i dont't fail at something that's truly important.
这样我就可以一直自我嘲弄的说,我没有成功是因为我没有努力过.
如果我努力了,那么我早就成功了.
I can alwa ys regale with myself with the diea that well i didn't succeed but i didn't really try hard.
但如果你让自己知道了你想要什么,然后你努力了.
你也就为后续的失败满足了前置条件.
whereas if you let yourself know what you want and then you try,you also set the precondition for failures.
youtube上的,或者其它平台上的朋友,大家好.今天来的是Dr John deloney.
hello everyone.watching and listening on YouTube or one  of the associated podcasts.I'm here today with Dr John deloney.
他是own your past,change your future的作者.
我们讲讨论这本书.我也很开心能和另一个医师进行交流.
he's the author of own your past change your future.We are gonna talk today.Im  very happy to do this,talk to another clinician.
关于你的人生就是一个经历,你通过经历中来观察世界,
以及当事情走向偏差时,你经历就会随着发生的变化
about the fact that you live your life through a story that you see the world through a story what that stody might be like when things are going wrong.
我们也会提及你的身份和身份的变化和发展
How it might be approved and also to talk about identity and its tranformations in the most practical possible way.
我们有大多可以谈论的事情了.我们可以从你为什么对经历感兴趣开始,John
and so um there are specifics that we can talk about but that's a good place to start what got you so interested in stories
我先了解到了精神创伤的后果会在人身上潜伏10-30年,
因为这个,我开始对过去经历感兴趣.
um I I think it I reverse engineered my way into it um it was learning the trauma narrative that played out in the human body 10 15 30 years later after the initial trauma
我以前一直认为人生故事就是经历,过去就过去了.
我一直没理解到,来引用van der kolk的话,我的身体在一直在我不知不觉的情况下,
在与过去经历做斗争.
and so I've always thought stories were narrative right there was something I thought about I did not understand that my body was keeping the score to quote van der kolk right that my body was revving up in fighting battles that  I didn't even know was happening
然后我们通过长期数据看到了,人们因为儿童时的经历中风,
癌症心脏病发作.这让我认识经历在各个方面上都有影响.
and so we're looking at the long-term data man and people are having strokes and cancer and heart attacks from from childhood experiences and that made me step back and go whoa there's there's these different layers to these stories happening all over the place and
当我思考后,我发现经历不只是过去的事情.它是我们整个人的一部分,是人生经验的一部分.
it's not just narrative it's it's the entire ecosystem that I call my body right my Human Experience and then as I began to pull the thread on those man
这些经历是我们不可分割的一部分.他们决定了我们生活的经验,
他们构成了我们对自己是谁的认知.
um those stories were born into and the stories we were told have such a formative shaping of of of our life experience and those stories become the stories we tell ourselves
我们作为精神医生从业者知道经历定义了一切.让我们知道自己能干什么,
不能干什么,让我们知道知道自身的存在就是对自己最大的恶.
这些经历可以限制我们的发挥,也可以是我们美好生活的助推剂
which as we all know in mental health professionals that shapes everything who I think I am and what I think I'm capable or not capable of or I'm the worst thing to ever happen to me those stories are highly limiting or they are the jet fuel on and on a well-lived life right
如果我们能讨论这些经历,这会给我们带来极大的帮助
so if we can discuss those stories man what a shape-shifting opportunity for us
身体存储过去经历的想法很有趣,我对它的理解是,
yeah well that idea about stories in some sense being stored in the body is kind of interesting and so the way I conceptualize it is that
过去的经历在你的个性中显现,在你的目标中显现,在你的对世界的假设和认知中显现.
a story manifests itself in a in  personality in a set of goals and a set of assumptions about the world perceptions about the world and
如果你过去有不好的经历,其实所有人都有不好的经历,只是或多或少而已
if you have had terrible things happen to you in the past and that's pretty much true of ever of everyone although some people more than others
你的身体根据你过去的糟糕经历,到现在还念念不忘的糟糕经历,来计算当前环境下的危险程度
then your body computes the present danger of the environment based on how many things have happened to you that are terrible in the past that that aren't resolved and.
解决了的糟糕经历意味着你已经为它们开发了一个解决方案.
如果的心理生理系统还认为你曾经经历的的那些遭遇还依然存在在现在的环境中,
那么它会让你精神紧张就如同你即将要再次经历那些遭遇一样
resolved would mean that you had generated a solution for them and if you if your psychophysiological system assumes that all the danger that you were subject to Once is still present in the environment that it's going to set you on edge as if you're walking in dangerous territory
这样的心理生理上的后果就是,你在不知不觉中为了抵御潜在的危险,
将感知系统变得更敏锐,但这却比正常状态消耗更多能量.
and the psychophysiological consequence of that is that you're prepared for danger and that does such things as burn up excess resources because you're much more reactive and on point than you might otherwise be in an anxiety prone manner
这也使你的免疫系统得到抑制.因为你现在就在面临危险,你的身体已经顾不上长远的健康问题了
it also suppresses immunological function.because your body isn't that worried about long-term immunological Health if you're confronting an emergency.
你在你的书里谈论掌控你的过去.这对找到战胜过去挫折的手段有帮助.
这些手段可以让那些挫折不在是你心理生理上的负担,也可以让你再次遇到这些挫折的概率无限接近于零.
so that you you talk in your book about changing your past owning your past and it's useful to Define that you're likely to overcome a trauma let's say and no longer in some sense store it psychophysiologically if you've generated a causal story about the reason that the trauma emerged and then reconfigured the way that you're conducting your life so that the probability that a similar thing will happen to you is reduced to close to zero
这些不是发泄情绪,而是理解问题.
right it's not catharsis right it's understanding yeah
我觉得问题的根源就在我们现在社会在心理层面的特质.我们创造了一个指责的社会,
每件事有需要有人负责.我们只能对自己的生存范围进行无限切分
(为了让自己承担的责任更少?),直到我们脚下的方寸之间.
而你踏入到了我的区域就是对我或意识形态或物理上的侵犯.
the challenge there is I think we've following that thread all the way to our modern psychological ethos we've created a world that is based entirely on blame and like somebody else is responsible and so I've got to continue to cut and cut and cut and I reduce myself to a two by two square with which I can exist and if you enter my Square then whether it's ideologically or physically then suddenly you're affronting me and.
我认为掌控你的过去意味着,当你回首过去,
当然我们都知道记忆是个很主观的东西,我不在意当时到底发生了什么.我现在40岁了,
我现在更关注的是,当我选择重新沉浸在当时挫折之中时,
我的身体不会不经思考的下意识做决定,企图快刀斩乱麻.
而是它知道我在思考,在等待我大脑做出的决定.
I think there's something about owning your past I look at it more in terms of can I think through what I remember to happen have happened and by the way we know that memory is a disastrous like narrative Storyteller right so I care less about what actually happened and more I'm in my 40s I'm telling myself this story that happened can I tell that story can I relive that story and my body doesn't take off on me right it doesn't rush to solve the problem for me
记忆关键的一点就是它根本没办法提供一个客观准确的记录,
单纯因为这是根本不可能的,因为过去是个太过复杂的事务了.它更像是一个地图,
我在这里发生了一些可怕的事情.提醒我需要重新更新我的地图,从而让我不会落入同样的陷阱.
the thing about memory is that it's not there to provide an accurate objective record of the past which is in fact impossible because the past is so unbelievably complex it's more like a navigation tool which is I went here I fell into something terrible and now I need to re-calibrate the navigation map that I'm using so that I don't fall into the same hole.
我觉得在听的观众你们需要知道的一点就是,
如果一个已经发生了18月的记忆还在不断,不自主的在你的记忆里纠缠着你.
当它出现的时候,你的身体不自觉得产生压力,
因为它还觉得你仍然在危险之中.
and you know one of the things that people might want to know who are listening is that if you have a memory that's older than about 18 months and it haunts you and when it comes up involuntarily it produces a stress reaction what that means is that as far as your nervous system is concerned and so as far as your body's concerned that danger hasn't gone away.
这是因为有一个潜意识的警报系统在不断的探测可能的危险,
它在提醒你,你现在用的地图是一个不完善的,继续使用会使你再次掉落进之前的坑中.
and what's happening is an unconscious alarm system that's looking for pitfalls and holes is warning you that the map that you're using is incomplete in a manner that might might enable you to fall into the same hole.
一个针对这个很好的策略就是,与其等待过去的挫折不由自主的浮现,
不如主动的刨悉你比以前的那个你发生了什么样的变化,什么改变了,什么没改变,
以及想一个策略来,如果同样的情况袭来,
你该如何比之前站在一个更有利的位置上
,and so one of the things that people can do that's very useful is if you have memories like that that plague you is to bring them to mind voluntarily instead of waiting for them to come after you involuntarily and then to Think Through what has changed and what might not have but also to come up with a plan so that if a similar circumstance arose you'd be in a better position in one way or another to deal with it.
世上没有其它办法能让一段记忆消散,
如果只是一遍遍的用相同的思维反复回想.
这段记忆会一直纠缠你.它会出现在你的幻想里,
出现在你的梦境中,出现在你与他人的对话里,只因聊天的话题涉及了它.
话题可能是关于一次失败,而你过去的经历就是一次失败.
如果你手中的地图并不能有效的让你超越过去的挫折的话,你大脑中确定危险的那部分是不会让你忘记挫折的.
there's no other way of getting the memory to go away like merely re-contemplating it in the same manner over and over won't do it and allowing it to plague you unconsciously it'll do that forever until you solve it it might show up in your dreams it'll show up in your fantasies it'll trigger you so to speak when you're talking to other people if they happen to discuss a topic that's related to it and it's because that the narrative is one of failure and defeat the event was one of failure and defeat and if there isn't a map to allow you to transcend that that's functional then the part of your brain that is concerned with identifying danger is never going to let you go.
我认为,我们在文化上创造出了这种病态的不安(逃避?),
你刚才表述的很清楚,唯一救赎的办法就是微笑的面对他,尝试开始解决问题.
如果继续选择逃避,只是在怪罪你当初的行为的话.你就是过度分析一切.
而直面恐惧则允许你的身体通过和别人的关系以及生活中的其他事逐渐的康复
yeah and I I think culturally we've created a pathology of discomfort and as you just outlined so eloquently the only way through this is to turn and face it and walk directly through it right and if you continue to run from the memories and pathologize and Chase the behaviors you end up with our over diagnostic approach to everything instead of turning and facing these things and letting your body heal through relationships and other things in your life
hhh 我们只是在重复你之前说过的话,你说了好几次了.你逃避的越多,
你的身体就越以为你的挫折在战胜你,因为你在朝着远离挫折的方向逃避.
这会不断加强你的挫败感.你逃的越远,你心理层面上的疾病越强.但唯一治愈的手段就是面对.
我们给我们自己创造的文化确告诉我们要尽一切可能远离一切的不安.但面对问题是唯一的解决途径.
um man we just end up chasing your tail and you   the more you run the more your body thinks it 's winning it's getting away from this stuff so it actually reinforces the anxiety it reinforces some of these um like psychological ailments the further you run from it the only healing is through it and in the culture we've created for ourselves says that uncomfortable discomfort is bad and it's to be avoided at all costs it and it's it's the only path to Healing
广告
如果逃避,你的大脑就会接收到你逃避的东西已经超出你的能力范围了,所以你就很自然的选择躲避.
而躲避是会导致焦虑的.当然直面恐惧不是一件容易的事情.
所以你在你的书里提到了一系列的方法可以帮助直面恐惧.
比如可以帮助你区别恐惧的方法,恐惧也有大有小,当然柿子挑软的捏.
if you run then the signal that the story you're acting out is that the  thing you're running from is bigger than you and that you have to hide and that's just a recipe for anxiety now it's not necessarily that easy to turn and face something but you do detail out a variety of strategies in your books that might help people do that you can you can differentiate the problem like you might you might have been traumatized at work let's say
我们就不用专业词汇了.如果你在办公场所遇到了极大的麻烦.
你的上司是一个暴君,你觉得工作真的很没有意义,这些想法一直在纠缠你,
以至于到了打扰你休息的地步.你尝试摒弃这些念头,但无一成功.部分原因是重新找一个工作实在是太吓人了,你没办法承受.
or let's not use that sort of jargony that jargony phraseology you may be having tremendous difficulties at work you might bedealing with people who are tyrannical at work and find it very meaningless and so and that's bothering you constantly it's disturbing your sleep for example and It's haunting you and you're you tend to try to push it out of your mind when the thoughts come and partly that's because the thought of how getting a new job is so daunting that you can't face it and.
一个解决方案可以是把一个大问题分成几个小但仍可以解决的自问题.
还是以工作举例的话,就是你感到不开心想找到一个新的工作,第一步可以是打开你的简历.
虽然你可能找不到一个新工作,但是你至少打开了你的简历.
one of the ways of re-calibrating that is to break down the problem into small and manageable steps and so for example one of the things that you can do if you might have to consider getting a new job because you're unhappy and miserable at work is open up your resume or your CV and look at it right so you might not be able to get a new job but you might be able to open up your resume and look at it and
这样做你开启了伟大征程的第一步.
你可以在接下来的一个月,每周花一个小时改你的简历,也可以每天花10分钟改一下,
也可以每两天花10分钟改一下.技巧的关键就是把一个骇人的,让你恐惧到逃避的怪兽,变成一个你能处理的程度.
and then having done that you've sort of cracked the surface and then maybe you could spend an hour a week for a month updating it or 10 minutes a day or 10 minutes every two days something like that but part of the trick is to take these larger monsters that are frightening enough so you want to run away from them
你在你的书里提到了你问了很多人为什么觉得有些事情事会他们感到焦虑不安.然后让他们写原因,
然后问他们自己为什么认为这些是正当的理由,然后开发一个计划来处理各个理由
you lay out for example in your book you ask people a lot of different questions about what they're thinking and if something is making you anxious and Afraid and miserable it's very useful to lay out to write out all the reasons it's making you anxious and miserable and to ask yourself what is it you're afraid of and then to develop a differentiated plan for dealing with those.
让我问你一个问题,在你精神分析的职业生涯中,
到底有没有人,到底大多数的人能不能靠自己做的我们说到的这些.
因为我发现不管从现代人的心理的每个问题出发,
我都得到了同样的答案,就是现代人绝望地,病态地,心灵层面地,吓人地孤独了
so let me ask you this in your psychoanalytic experience can somebody can the majority of people do this by themselves because I if I was to distill down all of the pathologies in modern civilization I keep coming back to a central one Central Point and that's that we are desperately and pathologically and spiritually and frighteningly lonely.
我在想我们是否还能告诉一个21岁的男孩/男人,你得自己独自做这件事
yeah and I'm wondering if we we can is it even possible anymore to tell a 21 year old boy 21 year old man hey you need to do this by yourself.
我一直反复的考虑这个.如果你想做成某事,第一件事就是加入一个团体.
加入一个帮派,手机里找几个可以交流的人,或者找个导师.找到能与你坐到一起的人.
or is the because I I keep coming back to,the first thing you do before you start trying to solve your problems is get a tribe get a gang get a couple of people in your phone or get a mentor
somebody you can sit with
虽然有我们有专业化的心理医生,但在你身边汇集一些朋友,你可以以人为镜可以明得失.
大家互相从彼此身上学到什么.因为我们就快要孤独致死了
um and in our we've had to professionalize it with mental health professionals but get some people around you to help be a good reflective mirror for you because we just we're loneling ourselves to death I feel like yeah well
我并不觉得人们能自己做这些事,这些事还是有些难度的
I don't think  that people can generally do this alone,it's actually very diffcult.
我认为人们不能部分原因是,我不是在讽刺大家,是人类不太会思考也不太会谈判
i think people can't do this alone in part because people,and im not being snide about this,people aren't very good at thinking and they're not very good at negotiation.
当我们焦虑的时候,我们的大脑并不会理智的思考,
即使我们面前只是好喝啤酒,
它也只想让我赶紧离开让它不安的地方.是的,这是另外的问题了
we're when we're anxious our brains shut off rational thinking right it doesn't want us wondering is that a nice bear just wants us getting out of there well that's that's and that's an additional problem.
你知道真诚在沟通中的重要性就是因为真诚和沟通以及思考并没有什么区别
所以你问人们是否能独自进行,常规的答案就是不行
.yo u know part of the reason that Honesty in speech is so important is that there isn't any difference between honesty and speech and thinking so you said can people do this alone and the answer to that generally is no .
因为思绪本身就是一个对话的过程.我们之间现在进行就是思考,我们与观众一起思考,我们为观众一起思考.because thought itself is generally a dialogical process so what you and I are doing right now is thinking things through now we're doing that with an audience and for an audience
讨论的之前我们都有自己的想法.
讨论的时候,我们在相互争论也在配合,我们允许讨论改变我们的想法.所以我们允许讨论改变我们的经历.
but you have some propositions and I have some propositions and we're we're pitting them against each other and cooperating at the same time and we're allowing the discourse to modify  our implicit presuppositions so we're allowing the discourse to modify our stories
思考本身就是一个内在的双方对话机制,当然也可以是三方对话机制.
如果你水平很高的话,你可以让你自己分饰三角,每人有自己的观点.
thought itself is internalized dialogue or trialogue if you're really sophisticated maybe you can break yourself into three people internally and have an argument
但让一人去发展一个系统性的内在的思考方式去
对抗另一个内在的系统的思考方式是非常困难的,更别说他得自己进行.
but it's very very difficult for people to develop a systematic approach to thinking and then to counter that with another internalized systematic approach to thinking and do all of that alone
在一个正常的社会里,如你所说的那样
generally what happens in a healthy society as you're pointing out is that
我们身边有陪伴我们的人,我们可以向他们表达我们的忧虑,他们会给我们回应.
事实就是,我们现在建议让人一个人自己做这些事,就表明人们现在有多自闭和孤独.
we have people around us to whom we can express our concerns and then they react and then you react to that and that's thought and the fact that we would even ask people to do that alone is an indication as you pointed out of how isolated and
朋友是你可以告诉好消息的人,告诉坏消息的人.你需要朋友是因为他们使你保持清醒
you know you said friends or people you can tell good things to and people you can tell bad things to and you have friends because friends keep you sane.
我喜欢你书的一个原因就是你主张现实生活的各个行为构成了你精神正常的状态.
它不是大脑中的孤立状态.
它是一系列复杂交错的正常等级(hierarchical)关系的成果.
如果一个人单独完成自我抛析,那么你也能在禁闭室里完成.
and this is one of the things I liked about your book is this insistence that sanity in some real sense is distributed it's not something inside your head it's something that you find as a consequence of being nested in a sequence in a hierarchical sequence of proper relationships and so if you could do it alone man you could do it in solitary confinement
即使罪犯也恨禁闭室
you know even anti-social criminals hate solitary confinement
我们毕竟还是社会化的.对的,这是我们惩治罪犯的手段.我们把他们放到一个坑里.
我们创造了一个我们想要生活的社会(一个把罪犯放到坑里的社会?)
we're social it's it's the way we punish prisoners right is to put them in the hole and we've just created a society where that's where we choose to live
我喜欢把社会看成平均分配的,我们每个在不同的时间互相帮助彼此.
yeah I love the idea of um I like to think of society it's it's evenly distributed we carry each other's burdens in different seasons
这才是生活的样子啊.
当我妻子生病的时候,当我老父亲去世的时候,我也想有人如同Hur/Aaron帮摩西一样帮助我.我们需要朋友帮助我们渡过这些困难.
um and that's the way through there's just simply moments when my wife gets sick or my dad finds himself my aging father is passing away that right that's the old you know holding your arms up in the desert narrative right like it we need other people to help us navigate these and.
我不想把我的经验应用于你的婚姻里,但是在我结婚的20年来,
很多次我告诉我的朋友我妻子的一些观点.
他们都会赞同她的反对我的.我需要他们作为磨刀石来帮助我重构我的观点.
ow many uh I won't I won't put my experiences into your marriage but the number of times over the two decades I've been married that I've been hanging out with some friends that I trust and I say my wife said this and this and my friends go man she's right you're an idiot right and so I need that sort of iron sharpening iron right to help me reframe something that my body's taken off on
精神正常的一个很好定义就是人们能忍受你在他们身边晃悠,他们还愿意给你正反馈
yeah well a good definition of sanity in some real sense and and I don't mean this in a trivial or a Coy way is that you're saying if you can behave well enough that other people can stand having you around so that they can provide you with corrective feedback
如果你是明智的话,你的朋友会愿意呆在一身边,他们会在你该被奖励的时候奖励你,会在你该被惩罚的时候惩罚你.
and if you're sane enough so that other people can stand having you around they'll reward you when you deserve to be rewarded and they'll punish you when you deserve to be punished and
只要你关注你朋友给你的反馈,你就会变得不讨人厌和找到自己在社会关系中合适的位置.all you need to do is pay really careful attention to that feedback and you'll be sane and properly situated.
这个观点是有效的前提就是整个社会环境没有走向病态的发展.
如果社会这样发展的话,会使问题更加复杂,而且社会朝病态发展也不是一次两次了.
now you know that can go wrong if the entire social community takes a pathological turn and that makes things more complicated and that does happen from time to time
即使如此,从普遍的情况来说的话,你还是需要被人所包围,
来陪伴你走下去.能一个人,没有亲密关系的人,还能进行社会化活动的人,还是太少了
but generally speaking you have to be surrounded by people and so we could walk through that very few people can function effectively without an intimate relationship
单纯是因为没有人来帮助你在中长距离来督促你的话,如果你没有亲密关系的话.
如果你没有中长远的目标的话,那你又如何智慧清醒的安排现在的生活呢?
that's because you don't have anybody who's monitoring you over the medium to long run if you don't have an intimate relationship and so how can you how can you organize yourself intelligibly  and sanely without the medium to long-term orientation.
你做不到的.你如何自予一个文明人而不与你亲密的人长期的接触呢?
你需要亲密的关系,你需要你的长辈,亲戚孩子.你需要同伴
you just can't do it and how can you tell if you're being a civilized human being if you're not bouncing your behavior off someone really close to you continually you you can't that's right you need the intimate relationship you need the family parents and siblings children for the same reason and you need friends .
你在书里花了大篇幅讲述同伴.你提到了很多实用的建议.我们应该在这方面多聊聊.
you talk a lot in your book about friends and you have some good practical advice I would say and this would be something for us usefully to concentrate on
你在书里提了好多如何交朋友.现代人真的不会交朋友,你可以分享一些这方面的经验与正在听的人.
I would say is you talk about how people can make friends because people really don't know and so maybe you could share some of that with people who are watching and listening
我认为主要有两个方向.让我们回到我们现在这个谈话.我认为这个谈话是一个很好的前端实验.
从人类历史来看,如果不是和我们坐到同一个屋子里,其它人是没办法听我们之间的对话.而距离远近就代表着关系的亲密,
yeah I  think there's there's two tracks I want to follow and one uh we can Circle back to this conversation we're happening that we're having right now evolutionarily is I think we're running a fantastic experiment because for all of the history of mankind nobody could sit in and listen to you and I dialoguing this way unless they were in physical proximity which that physical proximity is a form of intimacy
过去的话,要听我们之间谈话的话,人们得开两个小时车赶到这边,我们会在一个屋子里吃饭,我们在篝火旁交流.
而现在人们可以在旅行途中,听我们的交流,就如同他们同我们在篝火旁一样.我们创建了一种某种程度上古怪的智力上的亲密关系
we're all in the same room sharing the same meal sharing the same fire and now we've created this bizarre intimacy where people can drive to work for two hours you know one way and they can go on road trips but they're sitting by the fire with us right and so there's this this intellectual intimacy that'shappening
因为如此,我觉得在交朋友的层面上,我们的身体在哭泣(智力上的亲近不是真的亲密?)
but I think our bodies are hollering at us when it comes to making friends
我曾经一个季度内距离我的妻子两千英里之外,也曾距离她只有两英尺.
I spent a season man I was two inches from my wife and I was 2 000 miles away from her and
我和我喜欢的人同床共枕,但我仍感觉极度的孤单.我以前一直以为孤独是只有无人陪伴才有的感觉
I shared a bed with a woman that I loved and I was profoundly lonely and I always thought lonely was um proximal right you have nobody around you and
所以现在我认为孤独有两种性质,物理距离和情感距离.我觉得我已经熟悉了独自一人的感觉,我本身就是个内向的人,就是一个Nerd.
so I think it's proximal and it's emotional I've I've mastered the art of being alone I'm an introvert by Nature just a nerd
我喜欢读书,我在热闹的氛围里可以同时做到打招呼和沉浸在自己的世界里.
这种行为有其生理,精神上的损耗.我不想再因为自己没有性格怪罪自己.我想学新的技能,交朋友的技能
I love to read my books and so I I mastered the art of being alone in a crowded room I can wave and smile and be completely on my own planet and that has a physiological and a spiritual cost to it and so what I had to stop doing was beating myself up for having a lack of character or I'm a failure no I I needed I needed to learn a new set of skills and that skill set was making friends.
当还是小孩子的时候,上中学的时候,上大学的时候,一切的事情都是包括集体.
一起玩耍,一起休息.一切事情都是集体一起做的.当你走向社会,走出军队的时候,世界告诉你,现在到你决定你要干什么的时候了.
when you're a child when you're in middle school when you're in high school when you're in University everything is geared towards Community you play games together you don't play games together it's all about doing things together and then you cross that graduation stage or you get out of the army and the world looks at you and says it's now you versus everybody and
而我觉得我们并没学会这项技术.那我们该怎么做呢.
我们把这个东西想的太过复杂了.
我认为好客是第一步.邀请别人来你的地方,参加你的活动,你的爱好.迈出第一步.就如同你突然决定不再抽烟一样,你决定开始交朋友.
and so I think we just have to say hey I don't have the skill set so what do I got to do I think we overthink it I think Hospitality going first asking people over to your house to your events to your thing and just go first get over yourself look at it as you just got to quit smoking at some point um ,,just got to make friends at some point
我需要主动的迈出第一步,人们有可能会拒绝我.
我有可能找不到愿意在我身边的人.这样的话我得思考自身,
为什么我在世界里的投影会让人不愿与我度过时光呢
i'm gonna go first people are going to say no they're going to challenge you you're going to find out that nobody wants to be around you so you got to go to the mirror and ask yourself what is it about me that I'm projecting in the world that nobody wants to spend time with me
这个行为的确有挑战性.但不要再想太多了.不寻常的好客起来吧,迈出第一步吧
it really challenges but man just let's stop over pathologizing let's just go be weird Coco be weird and be hospitable go first go first yeah
你说你是个内向的人,关于内向的人一点就是他们得主动学如何社交.而外向的人他们太倾向那个社交,以至于无师自通了.
yeah well you know you you said that you're an introvert and the thing about introverts is they often have to learn consciously how to socialize right because extroverts that's right well they're tilted so hard in that direction it just comes naturally to them
我们可以下以行为学角度,该如何度过交朋友的初期阶段,我觉得人们会觉得它们有用
we could walk through some of the initial stages in forming relationships in a very behavioral manner because people might find that useful
本杰明富兰克林(美国国父?)曾说,当你入住一个社区的时候,你可以朝你附近的邻居寻求一些小的帮助.这会使你们走向互帮互助的方向
人们喜欢为他人服务,当你向别人寻求帮助的时候,你也被记下因果的债,然后你就可以回报他人了
so Benjamin Franklin said that one of the things you could do when you first moved into an neighborhood was to ask one of your immediate neighbors for a very small favor right and the reason for that is because it gets the reciprocal trade moving in the proper direction so people like to be of service to other people and if you ask someone to do you a very small favor then you put yourself in their debt and then you can also reciprocate
如果你请求的好的话,你给了他们一个展示最好自我的机会,你让他们展示自己积极,友好,乐于助人的一面.
这样的话,你就开始欠着别人的情了,你就可以开始回馈帮助了.
so you allow them to show themselves in their best light because you allow them to easily indicate that they're positive and friendly and willing to do something for someone else and they're very happy about that if you get it right and then you're in their debt so you can offer to do them a favor.
但是我们得承认这套行为和社会环境已经开始格格不入了.
我们不在朝邻居借东西了,有了亚马逊Prime,只要一晚上的时光,订的东西就能送到家门口.
我们不再让朋友送我们到机场,我们只要在手机上按个按钮,就有人来接我们了
but we got to be we have to be very honest about how counter-cultural that is now because overnight just with a snap of the finger we don't ask our neighbor for a cup of sugar anymore man we just get on Amazon Prime and it shows up at our house or we don't ask a friend to drive us to the airport anymore we just click a button on our cell phone and somebody comes and picks us up
我想的是,我们的文化已经从我需要你,你是我人生中重要的一部分,所以我才向你寻求帮助.
我才需要你听到我的声音.我才需要你给我个蛋,才你需要让我搭个便车,才需要你帮我搬家.
.and overnight I think we have shifted this idea from I'm going to honor you and allow you to be of service to me which is a gift and I'm going to allow my needs to be heard out loud I need some sugar I need an egg I need a ride I need you to help me move right
但现在,可怕的是,我们病态的认为自己是其它的人的负担.我们认为我们是朋友,
邻居的负担.我们怎么看自己都是负担.我们甚至觉得自己如果不存在这个世界,人们会过得更好.
这中想法是自杀的前置条件啊,我们整个文明在朝着这个方向一路前行
the worst call we've pathology we've suddenly become we think we're a burden Dr Peterson we think we are a burden to our friends and Neighbors and burdensomeness perceived burdensomeness the idea that people are better off without me that's one of the pillars of suicidal ideation and we our entire civilization has run that way.
我们视自己为负担,以至于朝别人寻求帮助这个行为,在当代,都被认为不是一个选择.
we are we've consider ourselves a burden and so the very Act of asking a neighbor to help with something is an act of defiance in our current era.
快去向别人寻求帮助吧.如果你想被人认为疯狂的,反当代文化的,赶紧去向别人寻求帮助吧
go for it man you want to be crazy and you want to be counter-cultural ask somebody to help you with something what a gift
当你搬进一个新社区的时候,你可以找一个当地的咖啡馆,
你可以在接下来的几个月内,每周一次或两次在相同的时间进去.
you know well you can also do things if you move to a new neighborhood for example you can there'll be a local cafe somewhere you can go there once a week for like several months or twice a week at a regular time.
你也可以把自己介绍给咖啡店的老板,工作人员.说你刚搬到这个地方.你逐渐成了那个地方的熟面孔.
当你感到安全的时候,你可以和其他的顾客交谈.
你也可以在当地商店里做这些事.
and you can introduce yourself to the owner and you can tell them that you've moved into the neighborhood and you can introduce yourself to the waiters and the waitresses and you can become a known fixture there and you'll start to feel comfortable there and then you'll be able to start to have conversations with people there and you can do the same thing with people at your local store.
你知道嘛,我有病人甚至不知道该如何介绍自己.这是人们沟通的障碍.
当你和人交流的时候,你注视着他们的眼睛,你观察他们的面部表情.你在观察他们如何反应.
你的潜意识的社交能力会自然帮你完成剩下的.
you have to and you know I had clients who didn't even know how to introduce themselves properly which can be a real impediment for people so you know you say to someone well you look them in the eye because then you're watching their face and then you can see how they're reacting and your unconscious socialization abilities will kick in
如果进了对的店,你可以说,大家好,我是Jordan Peterson.
我刚搬进这个社区.我会经常来你的店逛逛.所以我来介绍自己了.
然后你把你的手伸出去,然后看着他们,把你的注意力放在他们身上,而不是你自己身上.
if you attend to the right queues you say hello there I'm Jordan Peterson I just moved into the neighborhood I'm going to be dropping into your store pretty often.I thought I'd introduce myself and then you stick out your hand and you look at them and you make sure that you're paying attention to them and not you
待你说了这些后,你看周围人是否积极回应了你.如果不是的话,是时候去下一个街边小店了.
and you say what's your name and everyone responds positively to that there and maybe if they don't then it's time to find a different corner store
当你遇到一个人,但你忘记他的名字的时候,你可以说,
我们之前在街边小店遇到了,但我真的很不擅长记住名字,你能在告诉我一次你的名字嘛?
这样做的的话,那个街边小店不再是一个很陌生的环境,你的感觉对这个小店会慢慢安心下来.
that's right you know and then you try to remember their name but if you don't you say you know we met the other day but I'm terrible with names I forgot your name could you tell me again and if you do that then you know that little corner store then it's not completely foreign territory and you're not alienated from it you're going to start to feel comfortable
这对你每周必去的地方也适用.你必须得建立这些社会化的行为.
不然的话,外界都是敌人的地界.而你这样的话,起码这些地界不再陌生.而生活在敌人的地派是一件生理上挑战的事情.
因为你不知道你是被朋友所包围还是敌人
and the same thing is true for this place you might go every week you have to establish these routines of socialization because otherwise you're in enemy territory at least on known territory and that's extremely hard on you physiologically because you don't know if you're surrounded by friends or fools.
这也适用于邻居.
and so it's the same with your neighbors
你这是呼吁一场社会变革.
你在呼吁人们,当他们搬入新的社区的时候,人们应该主动的伸出手,来介绍自己,然后倾听回馈.
这是革命性的行为,是具有变革力量的.you are proposing an act of Revolution by going to a new environment and sticking out your hand and saying hi my name is John what is your name and actually listening to the response that is a revolutionary act that is a that's a transformative.
我有一个12岁的孩子,我很注重我和他之间的关系.
他还在他发育承认的早期阶段,但很快就要被释放到外界,成为一个大人
I take my son he's 12 and so I've started being highly intentional about our relationship because I'm I'm in the early stages of of raising what is soon to be released in the wild a grown man and.
我们每周二都会在这个华夫饼连锁店吃早餐.我在尝试教导他过度慷慨.
我也有时会对介绍自己这种小事感到困难.所以在这家开在Nashville Tennessee华夫饼店开张的时候,我也在开始训练自己.
o we have breakfast every Tuesday at this establishment here in the States called Waffle House it's just a chain Diner and one of the Revolutionary acts I'm trying to teach him is the act of um uh radical generosity and I again I struggle with sometimes basic hi my name is and so the way I began doing this The Waffle House opened in our small town outside of Nashville Tennessee
我开始超额付小费(也得有钱才能这样干啊),
因为没人想在周二早上6点在华夫饼店工作.
我告诉我的儿子服务人员他们是好人,他们帮我们准备咖啡,果汁,我们要好好对待他们.
I started over tipping in a in a significant way because nobody wants to be working the 6 a.m shift on a Tuesday at a waffle house and so I told my so hey we're gonna take care of these these waitresses they're awesome they bring us coffee they bring us juice they're lovely
只需要几个月他们记住了我的订单.当我走进商店的时候,我们在朝我微笑.这改变了我的社交行为.
现在我不仅愿意和我的孩子一起度过时光,也愿意和他们谈论他们好看的文身
and within a few months they know our order when we get there they are smiling when we walk in and it has absolutely transitioned our social interaction now I look forward to spending time with my son but also hanging out with these great waitresses and asking about their cool tattoos right
关键就是你要主动出击
but it's just going first it's just going first going first going first yeah
过度的慷慨在这些情况下的确有用,因为它有效的把你和其他买了就跑的顾客区分开来.
well that emphasis on somewhat excess generosity in those situations is extremely useful too because it doesn't take that much to distinguish yourself on the attentional front from the run of the mill customer
你知道吗?在你日常生活的地方,大概只有十个你经常去的地方.
而你你只需要十个以下你熟悉的地方,你就能很好的适应这个环境.你说你经常和你的儿子一起去这里and you know you only need Imagine This you probably only need between 10 maybe under 10 places to go in your social community in order to be well situated and so you said is it every week you do this with your son
是的.那我们来做些有关它的算术.整个流程大概要花多长时间啊?
yes sir okay so we could do some quick arithmetic around that how long how long in all does that whole event take
每周二,大概45分钟从我们坐下到我把儿子送到学校.
uh we are by the time we sit down and I get him to school late every Tuesday it's probably a grand total of 45 minutes
路上的时间呢?
okay and what about travel time
来回大概各占20分钟,所以全程大概一个半小时.
it's probably 20 minutes there so it's about an hour and a half okay so it's 90 full circle
所以每周90分钟?
it's 90 minutes and that's once a week
是的.你大概每天清醒16个小时,12个小时用来做有用的事,比如陪伴你的孩子,还有4个小时用来自我维护.
yes sir okay so then you figure you're awake for about 16 hours a day and of that awake time say 12 hours is useful for doing the sorts of things that you're doing with your son because you're going to spend four hours in just self-maintenance right so
90分钟大概是12个小时的十分之一(是八分之一).我们这只是大约的估算,为了方便计算.
你给一天的十分之一分配了任务,一周有七天
let's say 12 hours 90 minutes is about approximately one tenth of that we'll just use that as an approximation for easy mathematics so you've you've fixed ten percent of one day and there's seven days and
你这就把你人生的百分之三(是0.017%)给固定到一件具体的事情上来了
你只需要再找30(56)件这种事,你的人生就被百分百占满了
so that's basically three percent of your life you fix by doing that and that means you'd only have to fix 30 more things and you'd have fixed a hundred percent of your life.
你在书里提到你的一个朋友,他在谈论运动和健康.
他说你得改变你每天都在干的事情.因为你每天都干的事情定义了你的生活.
well you know how about you tell a story in your book about one of your friends who was talking about exercise and health and he said to you change the things you do every day the things that repeat those are your life
你的生活建立在这些每天都做的事情.人们太看重特殊的纪念日了.他们不太注意每天发生的这些事
that's the routine around which your life is built people very much overvalue special occasions and vacations and that sort of thing and they don't pay nearly enough attention to the kind of thing
你和你儿子做的事情,这就是你百分之三的人生了.
如果你能长久的做这件事,你人生中的百分之三就已经是好好度过了.你可以找下一个事情来做.
你可以和你的朋友做同样的事,可以和你的妻子做同样的事.
you're doing with your son it's like that's once a week you might be able to do that for years it's three percent of your life if you get that perfect now you've got three percent taken care of and you can move to the next small piece and do the same thing you do that with some friends and you you do that with your wife.
每周几次每次几个小时
for example a couple of times a week for a couple hours of sect ors a couple of hour sessions
我从的临床经验中得出,对开始一段亲密关系的人来说,你得至少和你的妻子
每周谈论90分钟的国内经济形势(????)或者你生活中的点点滴滴.
you know one of the things I found in my practice was that this is useful for people who are trying to embark on an intimate relationship is you need you need to talk to your wife about the domestic economy and the practicalities of your life together for about 90 minutes a week
你得和你的妻子每周至少一次约会90分钟,两次的话会更好,如何能安排的话.
如果不这样,你会逐渐变得孤寂和孤单.
你们之间会挤压出成堆的未完成的沟通.如果你不尝试完成他们的话,你们迟早会离婚,然后会花一生去治愈.
and you need to date at least once a week that for that length of time or or maybe twice if you can manage that and if you don't do that you will become isolated and lonely and you'll develop a backlog of communication and if you don't fix that you'll end up divorced,and then you'll be fixing it for the rest of your life
是的,是的呢.我喜欢这个积压的未完成的沟通这个观点.
就好像不断的往背包里往石头一样,背包迟早会重的让我走不动,如果我清理的话
absolutely absolutely and whenever a backlog of communication I love that I love that idea as though I'm just putting rocks in a backpack and eventually that backpack's going to wear me down if I don't have a regular practice of of communication and
我觉得这是一个伦理,性格,逻辑,技能上的问题.
我觉得就应该直截了当地告诉妻子,我也不知道怎么做,
我长大的时候也没看过我的父母做过这些.但是我想尝试一下.
也许我们可以抽出一点时间讨论我们的预算,我们想在什么事情上花钱.
again I somehow this became a moral or character logical issue I think it's a skills issue man I think taking some of the drama and smoke out of it and just saying hey I don't know how to I don't know how to tell you wife I've never seen it done I didn't see it at my house growing up I've never seen it I don't know how to do this so I want to practice once a week let's go over our calendar let's go over our budget like how are we going to spend money this
week
让我们开始尝试把,我尽量告诉你我这周需要什么
um and let's practice I'm going to try to tell you what I need this week
大约五年前,我的婚姻岌岌可危.
妻子和我意识到,如果我们的婚姻只能靠蜘蛛网一样的东西连接的话,但我们迟早要在灰烬中重构.
about five years ago my marriage was um I mean we were hanging on by a spider's web just hanging on and so my wife and I realized we we gotta if we're gonna hang on to this thing we're gonna have to rebuild it out of Ash .
我187厘米,88公斤.我生活在德州,是个德州男儿
I can't tell you I'm a six foot two 195 pound I lived in Texas my whole lifeTexas male
我下了极大的决心才告诉坐在桌子对面的妻子.我需要她在某些时候表示对我的自豪.
我当时并不知道在结婚后的5年里,我绝望地寻求她的认同
what it took for me to look across the table and tell my wife I just occasionally want you to tell me that you're proud of me that was a hard thing for me to say and I didn't even realize how desperately I've been searching for her approval for the firs 15 years we'd been married and
我一直不敢把我这个需求表达出来,我害怕她对我的批评.
我一直把她的不回应当成拒绝.我从来不敢把我的需求说出来.
当我说出来的时候,我时感到羞愧和自责的.而她告诉我的是,如果你15年前告诉我这个的话,我们会过上更幸福的生活.
现在她把这个当成我们婚姻的一部分.她说我看见你做了这些我感谢你对家庭的付出
how much I kept going out on a limb and on a limb and on a limb and I was taking her non-response as rejection and I never put my needs out there and I was embarrassed and ashamed to say it and then she said man that would have been super helpful 15 years ago and now she makes it a regular she makes it a regular practice of our marriage to say hey I see you and I appreciate what you're doing for our family golly what a gift and
我不知道清洗盘子会和前戏一样,如果我早知道的话,我愿意洗一天的盘子.不要只在脑子里幻想,你得把你的需求大声的说出来.
I didn't know that uh doing the dishes was akin to foreplay great I will knock those dishes out all day long it's about practicing saying your needs out loud and then man get out of your head
与其在锻炼视频里浪费的时间,不如去次健身房.
与其在脑中琢磨该如何告诉妻子,不如直接去告诉她.浪费了太多的时间.我们拥有了太多的数据信息,却不如直接去实践.the number of hours I've spent researching workout programs when I could have just gone to work out or researching how to tell your wife instead of just telling her what a waste of time we have we have too much data man we have too much information we need
to go do go do go act go well
你可以和你的伴侣来简略的讨论.让我们告诉彼此我们都需要什么.
而我们经常又太傻忘记告诉彼此我们需要什么,或者我们也不知道我们想要什么.我们也没尝试过去做这方面的事.
you can you can have a preliminary conversation with your partner let's say and say something like look we need to tell each other what we need and want and we're both too stupid to do that because we don't really know what we even want and we have almost no practice at it
但可怕又可悲的一件事就在于,当你想听到你的妻子对你感谢,骄傲的时候,比如你为家庭提供了住所.
当你向她表达出你需要从她那得到这样的反馈的时候,你同时把自己的不安,脆弱也展示在她面前了.
当你分享的时候,也告诉对方该如何更痛伤害你的办法.所以分享这种感情需要极度的信任.,
and worse here's something about that that's really quite sad and frightening is like you know if one of the things you wanted to hear is that your wife was grateful to you for let's say providing property for the family so say proud of you there's a a part of you that's quite insecure that wants that message and You're vulnerable on that point hey and so then if you share that vulnerability the person with whom you're sharing it knows exactly where to stick you if they want and so it's real trust to do that
但另一种情况是,人们经常说,你爱我,那么你肯定知道我想要什么.
第一,那是理想情况,那是完美的爱情,.第二我没有超能力,能读人心.其次你自己都不知道你自己想要什么,更别说别人了
but the alternative is assuming that and people do this all the time they'll say things like well if you love me you'd know what I wanted it's like well first of all that's a pretty perfect love and second I'm not Clairvoyant right yeah well right well you're not even smart enough to do that for yourself most of times,unless someone else.
你可以先和你的伴侣同意一些事,你说这是我想听你说的一些词,你能为我说这些词吗.
另一个人可能拒绝,他可能说刻意,太人工了,现在能说只因为我们在刻意锻炼
so you know you can make an agreement with your partner and say look um here's something I'd like to hear you say and here's the words I'd like to hear will you just say that another person might object and they'll say well that's that sounds  falsify  if I do it or it won't be real because we're just practicing it and it's it's artificial
你可以这样想,我们接下来要渡过30年,如果只需要20次训练的话,那20次训练只是十万天中微不足道的事情.
and then you think well wait a second we're going to be together for the next 10 000 days  if it takes yeah yeah or more and if it takes 20 stupid practices to get it right that's not so much stacked up over ten thousand days
关于大多数婚姻,我觉得至少有10件事是每个人想常规听到的.然后这10件事决定了婚姻的成败.
所以你更应该和你的伴侣坐下来说.我们要一起做决定我们需要什么,我们应该勇敢的表达自己的观点,即使以一个愚蠢的方式.
我们也应该在尝试的时候,允许自己犯错误
you know and it might be with many marriages I would say there's probably 10 things that each person wants to hear on a quasi-regular basis that would make the difference between the marriage succeeding and the marriage failing but it means you have to sit down with your partner and say look we should decide jointly what we need and want and we should have enough courage to try to express ourselves stupidly in the attempt to get it and then allow ourselves to make mistakes while we are practicing.
如果我为了维持婚姻做了一切.我会发现我最后追求的是个我不想追求的东西,这对我的伤害更大
I love that I find that we've become goal obsessed and so if I want to do these things so that I can keep my marriage I find that I end up way out on a limb I find out by chasing somewhere I don't want to go
我认为更有价值的人生不是追求快乐,因为快乐只是可卡因和棉花糖.而是追求满足.
I find it more valuable to say I want t live a life that is not not chasing happiness because that's just cocaine and cotton candy but I want to chase a life of joy
所有的数据向我表明,一个好的婚姻,与浪漫亲密对象的好的关系,是长期最大化满足的最好的选择
and all of the data tells me a good marriage a good connection with the Romantic intimate partner over a long period of time is the best bet I have in maximizing joy and
所以如果我想最大化满足的话,前期的尴尬是不可避免的
and so if I'm going to do that that means I've got to be awkward and
顺便说一下,如果你能裸体站在某人面前,我美嘛,说要一起搓澡吗
M.那么你也一定能说出,当我看到洗漱池里有未洗的盘子的,这让我觉得我不是一个很好的妻子,
因为在我脑海中,一个很好的伴侣应该能保证碗筷及时清理,你能帮我清理一下吗?
by the way if you can stand in front of somebody naked and say do you see me and you think I'm beautiful do you want to join bodies with me surely you can say hey when I see dishes in the sink it makes me feel like I'm not being the Romantic partner I feel like I'm less of a wife because I've created this narrative in my head that this is what a perfect wife does or a perfect husband does can you help with the dishes good gosh.
如果你能裸体的站在别人面前,那你肯定也能在洗碟子上面寻求帮助.
当你望向深远的时候,深渊也在看着你.
当别人给你反馈的时候,不要当成对你失误的指责,当成他们在请求你的帮助.
you can do you stand in front of somebody naked and say Here I Am surely you can say hey can you help with the dishes right and then we have to be stop being so um looking for people coming at us what's that great saying what have you go looking for in the world you're sure to find start receiving those that feedback as an invitation not as a you've been screwing this up right
当我向我妻子表达"你可以对我表示自豪的时候",
我的妻子并没有当成我对她的指责,即使她之前没有做到这些,
而是当成我在向她寻求帮助,一种可以更多表达她对我爱意的邀请
because my wife could have heard that me saying hey I just want you to say you're proud of me every once in a while as me throwing a grenade right you're failing me because you're not doing these things that's she took it as here's an invitation here's a way you can love me better and what a gift man what a gift yeah well
不要在自怨自哀了
you could get over ourselves man
你可以帮助人们从这类事情一个个单独看待,然后从最小的事情上开始着手
you can help people box those sorts of things in too by saying look let's make this discussion about the smallest thing possible
我们先不从最大的问题开始讨论,比如讨论夫妻俩之间婚姻的正当性这种大问题开始.我们先从改善最小的问题开始
right we're not we're not opening up Pandora's Box and assessing the validity of our entire marriage we're going to try to get one small thing slightly better
如果这样做的话,我假设很多事情会逐渐变好.
也许我们可以尝试每周坐下来90分钟来进行沟通.也许一开始90分钟太长,我们不需要一下子就做到
and we're going to assume that lots of things are going well and so we're going to sit down for 90 minutes a week maybe that's not all at once
我们可以在90分钟内分享我们在想什么,我们希望接下来会发生什么.然后我们可以看看这种谈话,有没有什么正面的效果
and we're going to share what's on our minds and we're going to talk about what we would like to see happen and how we would respond positively to that and
我们不要一上来就讨论超大的话题,因为讨论很容易就变成了对整个婚姻的批判.
这也是伴侣一般不会进行这种讨论的原因,特别是有一系列积压的话题没谈论时.
(他们在逃避.他们潜意识的知道讨论就会导致批判.我觉得在某种程度上,他们是在以逃避来保持婚姻,直到问题无法在逃避)
we're not going to LEAP to the conclusion that that's a generic criticism of the whole marriage this is partly also why people don't have these conversations hey especially when they have developed a backlog of communication
所以我和我妻子设了一些帮助我们来避免这种积压的讨论.有一条就是永远不要同意你不愿意的事.so my wife and I had a rule too which was well we had a couple of rules that helped us along with this to to not have the backlog and one of the rules was don't agree to anything that you don't agree to
我最不想听见的就是,一件事5年过后,你说我当初就不同意这件,但是我觉得你想做所以就跟着你做了
because the last thing well the last thing I wanted to hear five years down the road after we had embarked on a particular pathway was well I didn't really want to do that but I just went along with it because I thought you wanted to
说这句话,你想要我作出什么回应呢?逆转时空嘛.
5年前,我们讨论过这件事.我不想让你同意我,而你只是为了附和我而同意了.
而我当初想要的是我们看法一致.
it's like well what now am I what am I supposed to do about that you know that was five years ago and we talked about it and I didn't want you to agree because you thought it was easier to agree I wanted a consensus you know and so
而看法一致的结果就是,当我们坐下来讨论一个现在的问题的时候,
我们就不能把过去的事翻出来,我们的讨论就可以只为未来做打算.
and the corollary to that was if we're going to talk about something that needs to be addressed now and that will be fixed in the future we don't get to drag up the past
一直附和的还有可能导致,当讨论一个问题的时候,有一个说,你一直这样,你从来不有在乎我的感受,你未来也不会变得
because that's another thing that happens right is you start talking about things that are problematic and one person or the other goes well you've you always act like this you've always acted like this and there's no chance in the future that you're ever going to change.
你立马陷于到一场斗争当中,因为你的过去和未来都被否定了.
it's like well instantly you're in a fight because your whole character past present and future has just been Savaged
而一场正常的对话更应该像,我们的一餐可以过的更美好,
如果我们可以吃完饭你把碟子洗了/或者放到洗碗机里
when when the conversation should be something like uh our meal times might go 15 percent better if after you were done eating and you and we had all finished you brought your dishes to the sink and rinsed them off and put them in the dishwasher and
如果你做了的话,我愿意做这个做为回报.
and here's what I'm willing to do in return for that
而我喜欢说的更委婉一些,更私人化一些.
因为当有人要求我要做什么的时候,我的边缘系统就会被激活,
我马上变成了一个野兽,让本能告诉我是战是逃
well I like to I like to even take it one step further and personalize it because I find I react when somebody says you need to as soon as somebody points their finger at me I I just I am fully limbic man I go I go fight or flight instantly
所以我一般会说,我举个例子哈
and so I I tend to say heyuh here's a good example
我在那什维尔的Ramsey Solutions 工作.我们的服务就是营造一种团队的氛围,帮助他人付清他们的负债.
I I work here at Ramsey Solutions in Nashville and uh have a history of helping people get out of debt pay their financial debts off and work together as a community and as a couple to pay the debts off
我们经常遇到的问题其中之一就是,如何让我的伴侣同意开始偿还债务.
他想买大皮卡,他想买大别墅,他有一推的债务堆积起来.我一直告诉他这些数据,但他并不在意.
one of the most common questions we get is how do I get my partner on board like he wants to just buy a huge pickup truck and buy the biggest house and he's run the credit cards up and I keep coming to him with these numbers and
当你告诉别人,你要他们把皮卡卖掉的时候.你这是在开启一场战争.这和数字没有关系it's it's very short or it's not about numbers and if you come at somebody like you need to sell your truck and you do this well now you've started a war
而你坐下来告诉别人,你现在因为负债害怕地要死.这个和以前的说法还是有区别的
there's a difference when you sit down and say hey I'm scared to death and I can't breathe because we are so indebted
如果你能帮我把盘子收起来,帮我放在洗碗机里.这对我帮助很大.这样说的话,比较有情调.
there's something about saying it would really be a gift to me if when dinner was over if you took and rinsed your plate and just took six seconds to put in the dishwasher that'd be a gift to me
这和你命令我让我去把碟子收起来,有很大的不同.一个让我进入了防御姿态,一个是请求.that's different than you need to take your dishes out right in one of those puts me on the defensive one of those is an invitation and.
我觉得我的人生应该大部分时间在做请求,除了几个特殊的情况
I've just decided man my life is too short to continue to to do anything other than invitations except in very few moments
广告
你在负债那边提到的方法,也可以用来和家人,朋友,家庭沟通和配合.问题的关键就是对未来有同样的追求.
yeah yeah well that conversation about debt too is one of the ways that you cooperate and negotiate with your spouse and your friends your family for that matter is also to jointly develop something lik a joint vision
你可以和你的妻子坐下来说,如果我们想让我们的晚餐过的最完美的话,就像你和你的儿子一样,那晚餐该是什么样呢?
you know because you might be able to sit down with your wife and say well look if we could have the dinner times that we really wanted if they were optimal like you've done with your son let's say what would that look like.
假设你有好几个孩子,你们都想像个家庭一样坐下来吗?
这是一个给所有人的问题.我们所有人都得想,我们是否都愿意家人一样坐下来?
well let's say  you have  a couple of kids you think well do we all want to sit down together as a family that's a quick this has to be a question right to both of you yes that you're actually imagining
do we all want to sit down okay yes well
我们做这件事的频率是什么?一周七天都这样干嘛?这对我们家是很重要的一部分嘛?
我们一周五个晚上嘛?然后周五做些不同的事情.你想这些小事都可以商量.
how often do we want to do that like seven nights a week is this something that's actually a crucial foundation for our family or can we do it five nights a week and maybe do something different on Friday and you think well do all those micro things have to be negotiated
但关键就是这些不是小事,这些零零散散你每天都做的就是你生活的基石啊
the answer is those aren't micro things you do that every day they're absolutely foundational
你应该想听到别人的看法是什么,不然的话你就永远不知道别人是否和你拥有同样的看法.
也许有更好的看法,你不听你是永远不知道的
and and then you want to hear what the other person has to say because if you don't they're not going to be fully on board plus they might have a better idea than you you never know.
比如我们决定我们一周有五天坐在桌子前正常的吃饭,一天我们可以坐在电视前面.
随便吃点速冻的,一天我们出去吃.我们试下这种生活一段时间
it's like so let's say we decide well we're going to have dinner together at six o'clock five nights a week and we're gonna let people forage one night a week and and maybe sit in front of the TV and we're gonna  go out one night a week something like that.and we'll try that for a while and
下一个问题我们要吃什么呢?谁来做饭呢?谁来打扫卫生呢?
如果我们要继续下去,如何让孩子也参与进来呢?我们要不要尝试点新的食物?
then the next question is well what would we like to serve and who's going to cook and who's going to clean up and and if we wanted it to go as well as it possibly could how are we going to get the kids involved and do we want to experiment with some new foods
你知道吗,吃饭尤其是晚饭,它大概占90分钟.
这可是你一天的十分之一,这可是你一生的十分之一,这可以是货真价实你人生的十分之一啊.
and you know that meal time if that's the evening meal let's say that's 90 minutes that's more than one tenth of your day and so that's 10 of your life that's literally 10 percent of your life.
Jordan:如果你把你晚上安排好的话.
John: 你的收益就像复利一样大,一样利滚利.这就和把你的15%你的收入放到养老金的花,他会不断的增值,超出你投入的15%.
如果你能照顾好你每天的10%,你不仅是照顾好了你人生的10%.
突然之间,你的婚姻同步上了,你变成了更好的父亲,公民和工人.每个都在相互增幅.
if you get the evening yeah but it's bigger it's compound interest that grows over time I think that 10% you take care it's like it's like putting 15 % of your income in etirement it grows to infinitely more than 15 of your income over time yeah right so if you take care of that ten percent it's not just taking care of that ten percent suddenly if your marriage is in sync you're an infinitely better parent right infinitely better citizen infinitely better worker and it becomes a much very recursive .
那个著名精神医师William Glasser,它有一句话我特别喜欢,他说他可以用两次会话来修复任何婚姻
the uh uh the famed psychiatrist William Glasser he gave me I love this analogy he says that he could he his famed line was he could fix any marriage in two sessions
他说我们用图像思考,用语言表达.如果伴侣能思考同一张图像,那他门就有相同的道路.
and he said we think in pictures but we speak in words and if couples can simply align their pictures yeah then you get a very clear path
有天,我妻子在周一跟我说我们在周末来一场最性感的约会,然后她就径直走开了,
so when my wife comes to me on a Monday and says hey uh this weekend you and me we're gonna go on the hottest date and then she just walks away
我在周一晚上想我们要去哪.周二我在想我要穿什么,我们要去多久
周三周四,我在想谁要看小孩.我放弃了,因为我知道他们会好好的.我还要想我们会在那个酒店过夜.
,Monday night I'm wondering where we're going Tuesday night I'm wondering what I'm wearing and for how long right by Wednesday and Thursday I'm wondering who's going to keep the kids and I don't care because they're going to be fine and what hotel we're gonna end up at
等到终于到周末的时候,我穿了正装,而她一身休闲.我们相互问对方你在干什么.
我说我们不是要去约会吗?她说你在想啥,今天楼下玉米薄饼卷店,7个卷饼只要十块钱.我们要吃辣吃得过瘾.
and then Saturday comes along and she I show up in a suit and she shows up in her running shorts and a t-shirt and I say what are you doing what and she says what are you doing and I say I thought we were going on a hot date and she says it's seven seven tacos for ten dollars down at Taco Hut we're going on a hot date
嘿,我喜欢墨西哥卷饼.我也希望她喜欢偶尔的约会.
但我们用了同样的词语来描述我们心里想的不一样的场景.现在她不开心了,我也不开心了.hey I love tacos and I hope she loves the occasional Rendezvous but we both use the word date and we had very different pictures now I'm upset she's upset.
只要我不出差的时候,我们每天都会问自己,我们想象中的自己今天会干什么呢?
and we just so in our in my house every single day of the week every day I'm not on the road we ask ourselves this question hey what's the picture of today look like
这已经变成了我们每日的用语了
it's just become a vernacular in our home
所以当她说她晚上需要私人时间的时候.我想的是.在晚饭后,一起照顾完孩子后,在搓澡后,
我不会在你晚上最后的8分钟内打扰你
and so when she says I need some space this evening I need some time by myself I I tend to go okay cool after dinner and after the kids and after you're done riding enough I won't hassle you for the last eight minutes of the day for her
而她想的是,当你回来的时候,我就要出去了,我也许一周内会回来
she's thinking the moment you walk in this house I'm out and I might come back in a week right
我们需要我们脑海中的图像对得上
我对两种选择都可以,她对两种选择都可以
对上这些图像,让彼此清楚你到底是怎么想的.
we just have to align our pictures and I'm cool either way and she's cool either way it's just managing those expectations and being so clear with one another.
这就是建立一个共同愿景的过程
yeah well that's exactly the process of defining a shared vision and
有一点好处就是,这样做让你不会被动反应,让你不会措手不及,不会被被可怕的事物,怪物一类追赶
one of the things that's lovely about that is it makes you it you're not reactive then so you're not the thing that's being chased by the monster or the dread.
因为你们在不断构思你们共同未来的样子.这样你们就有机会分享一个共同期待.
理论上说,它对你们的整体好处远大于任何一个人做任何的事情.
you're the thing that's actively conceptualizing the manner in which the future is going to shape itself and what you have is the delightful opportunity to share a joint Vision that in principle would be better for both of you than anything you coulddo alone
你之前说,数据表明,在人生中能最大化健康和提高你感到满足的概率的一件事就是拥有长期的亲密关系.
like you said that all the data shows that one of the best things you can do in your life to maximize your long-term health and increase your probability of at least some Joy is to have a functional long-term intimate relationship and
所以你要注重培养亲密关系
而培养亲密关系的很重要的一部分就是建立出共同的愿景
so you have to attend to that and a huge part of that is the development of these shared visions and
小的共同愿景也是很有用的
it's really useful to to develop micro visions and
回到我们刚才说的(打断话题),有一对伴侣来找你咨询,你会对他们说什么呢?
他们有了一个三岁孩子的,还有了一个刚出生的宝宝,so you know we just talked what would you what would you tell what would you tell clients back in the day when they would come to you and they'd have a three-year-old and they would have just had and they have an infant they have child number two
他们说他们很久不搓澡了.我们有亲密关系,我们成为了我们家的共同管理人.你作为一个临床心理学家的回复是什么呢?
and they would say we're not having sex anymore we have like an intimacy we become co-managers of our house and your response as a clinical psychologist would be
我一般说你要定计划去完成它,要把它放进日程表里.
我听到的回复一般是,我们不想再做了.你会怎么继续跟他们说呢?
you've got to schedule it you've got to put on a calendar and the response always is I don't want to do that anymore.What's the followup?
这是个很好的问题.我的策略一般是问他们,你们想多久来一次呢? 人们真的是太恨这个问题了
that's a great question well my first response is well how often do you want to have sex and people hate that people hate that question and
所以他们尝试回避这个问题.他们一般会说我们不想在这方面计划的有条有序.行吧,随你们
and so they avoid it they say well you know we don't really want to be that calculating about it's like okay right whatever
我们准备把这个答案参数化.一年一次?是不是有点过少了?一天十五次?这是不是太多了?we're going to parameterize this once a year.it's like no that's probably too little okay 15 times a day it's like no that's probably too much.
可以.这样我们起码有了一些上下限,具体数值在一年一次和一天十五次之前.让我们看看能不能缩减这个区间.
okay so now we got some parameters here somewhere between once a year and 15 times a day let's see if we can narrow that in.
这个过程的确会让人们感到难受,因为他们不想明确说明自己的需求的
and this does make people uncomfortable right.they don't want to specify their needs and wants and.
这种难受到底来自于哪里呢? 我认为他们为自己需求什么而感到羞愧.这是一种根源上的羞耻感.what's this what's the source of that discomfort where does that come from I think they're embarrassed that they need anything it's fundamental shame.
这种羞耻感和在别人面前赤裸是同一种感觉.
他们不想和伴侣分享这种信息,因为这种行为是真情流入的,是需要揭露的
it's that same exposure of nakedness and then they're they're unwilling to share the information with their partner because it's revealing
他们害怕得到拒绝,他们害怕引起争论,他们有太多的原因不做这个了
and then they're afraid they're going to be rebuffed and they're afraid they're going to get into a fight they've got lots of reasons not to want to do it
这又回到了那些从小就追缠不休的那些经历
but then that rolls back to those stories that have been that have been haunting them since they were kids
他们在避免让这种艰难的对话有产生的机会.
right yeah yeah and and they don't want to have the difficult conversation up front,t and so we might say well
让我们讲下道理,我们还是要给一周定下几次的
okay let's let's be reasonable about this,it's going to be some number of times a week
你们都有工作,你们都有孩子,你们都很忙.
你们不可能每晚都约会你们没有时间做这个.那我们来理性的讨论下.
you guys have jobs you have kids you're busy you're not going to have a hot date every night you just don't have time for it and so why don't we be reasonable about it
我们可以把目标定为两次,我们也可以从一次开始尝试.一次已经比零次很多了
we can try let's aim for something like twice a week it's like can you think or maybe we could start with once a week because zero once is a lot more than zero,it's a lot more than zero and
然后你想,我们当初在谈恋爱的时候已经做了所有的约会.现在我们已经不想在约会了
so then you think well all right and then they say something like well you know we did all that dating when we were dating and and now we don't want to do that anymore
你到底在说什么?你是在说你不在想要任何浪漫,你不在想要任何搓澡?
你不在想付任何努力在上面.但却仍在暗自期待它会如魔法般发生,但很明显它是不可能发生的
it's like okay so what are you saying here exactly you're saying that you don't want any more Romance and you don't want any more hot sex and you don't want to put any work into it and it's just going to happen magically even though it's clearly not happening
这是你的理论,让我们来看看它是否可行
that's that's your theory and then let's let's run that theory out okay  so now
你现在有刚出生的小孩.等他们10岁,11岁的时候,你的生活会是什么样呢?
你的生活被你的家庭占据.而且你已经过了10年的没有搓澡和亲密关系的生活
you have new kids and that's going to be it's going to be like that for a few years maybe till they're 10 or 11.you're going to be occupied with your family and so now you have a sexless marriage with no intimacy for a decade
等到2032年时候的时候,在离婚法庭的上,你会是什么样呢?
so what does that look like in like 2032 when you're in divorce court
也许你那时候正在尝试从某种过瘾的东西恢复出来.比如工作,酒精,或者其它.
因为你身体总会找到能让它满足的东西,如果它满足不了它需要的那种关系的话.
如果它没办法得到一种深层次的链接的话,它会找廉价的替代品来满足它的需求
比如外遇
that's right how's that or you're recovering from some addiction right right so of of work or of alcohol or whatever it is because your body's gotta it's got to meet that need somewhere and if it can't get it if it can't get it a true deep connection it will come up with all kind of cheap substitutes right yeah like an affair
是的呢.你当然不这个想要这样的结局.这需要些艰难的对话来解决.
你想让你的婚姻在10年内逐渐劣化成地狱吗?这个可能性你听起来有什么感受呢?
that's right yeah so so of course you don't want to do this this requires difficult negotiation.how would you like to have your marriage deteriorate into hell over a 10-year period how does that sound as an alternative.
这个结局的确不怎么好?那么这两件事哪个更恐怖呢?
it's like well that's not very good it's like okay so which of these two things are you more afraid of and
如果人们真正想过这个问题的话,他们会想,我应该承担的起我的需求被人了解的风险
then the when people really think that through they think oh yeah well maybe you know I could take the risk of making what I want known
如果把这个相通的话,那接下来就是确定约会的细节了.
哪天晚上?多长时间?你们要找临时看孩子的吗?你们每周都出去约会吗?每个人在这个约会的负责的方面都是什么?所有的细节都需要讨论出来
then okay so now you specify it well a date which night how long how are you going to find a babysitter are you going to do this every week who's going to be responsible for what in relationship to this date all these details have to be negotiated and
还记得我们之前做的逻辑推理吗?如果一周约会一次,一次两个小时.
这是一天的15%,这是你人生的5%(2%),这是你人生中关于亲密关系的一部分
then we remember you know by the same logic that we've already employed if this is two hours a week then that's 15 percent of one day that's another five percent of your life and it's the intimate part of your life and
如果你能把这个事情管理好的话,你的人生有可能过的更开心.这可以是人生25(50)件事中的一个来帮助你过的更好
if you got that right my God you might be a much happier person and so that's another one of the only 25 things you have to take care of to set your life up
你之前问我为什么大家都不愿意展示自己的需求?大家都不愿意展示自己的脆弱啊
but I mean you said why are people afraid to do this is they're they're afraid to show their vulnerability man
他们不信任自己的伴侣,他们不知道如何协商,他们甚至不知道自己到底想要什么.
they don't trust their partner they don't know how to negotiate they don't even know what they want themselves
你也知道的,向别人承认自己需要别人的注意不是件容易的事情,但是事实就是每个人都需要别人的注意
you know like it's not that easy for someone to admit that they need any physical attention at all even though everyone obviously does
当你承认你需要别人的注意的时候,你也把自己置于危险之中,从某种意义上说,这就是亲密关系的定义.
you know because you're putting yourself on the line then and that is the definition of intimacy in some sense
广告
对的.我肯定你也经历这样的事
absolutely absolutely I I I can't tell you and I know you've experienced this too
不管是一个有三个小孩,想知道今天是周几的单亲妈妈,
还是一个拥有超过我想象能力的资源的百万富翁,他们很少能面对我坐下来,清晰的告诉我他们到底想要什么
whether it's whether it's a single mom with three kids just trying to figure out what day it is or it's a multi-multi-millionaire who's got resources that far exceed anything I could imagine ,I've I've rarely rarely sat down across from somebody and had them be able to articulate what do you actually want
他们没办法回答这个问题
They cannot answer that question
.他们用瘾,爱好,想分泌更多的多巴胺来当答案.
and they fill it with additions ,they fill it with hobbies,they fill it with dopamine chase.
他们用太多的东西当答案,却没人能真正的回答那个问题.你到底想要什么?
They fill it with so much stuff and nobody can answer that question.What do you want?
也许我们生活在一个没有共同愿景的世界,我们不知道作为一个整体我们朝向何方.
because I we just don't have a culture that has a shared vision of where we're headed
我们倒有个当我受伤了,是其它人的错的文化.我们习惯了指责别人.
we have a culture of you're hurting in somebody else's fault and let's let's start pointing fingers
我们真得调转车头,朝着一个共同愿景的方向前进
and man we've got to circle the wagons on a shared Vision moving forward yeah
现在已经没人会问自己想要什么了.大家问的都是自己不想要什么,为什么我会感到这么难受
because what do you want no that's not a question anybody asks it's what do I don't want and why am I feeling just uncomfortable
是他们,是他害我这么难受的
it's about them it's because of him it's because then
如果你一直在问你不想要什么,你就一直被你的负面感情所驱使.是的,你是在逃避,不是在面对
well then if it's what you don't want you're driven by negative emotion.That's right,u are running from,not to.
而如果你被一个正向的愿景所驱使,且有远见的方式处理积极的事物,你因此会产生积极的情绪if you're driven by a vision that's positive emotion because approaching something positive in a Visionary manner generates positive emotion
如果你一直在逃避你不想要的事务,你就会一直在一种紧张沮丧的状态中.这就是大脑运作的规律
if you're only fleeing from things you don't want then you're constantly in a state of anxiety and depression that's how it works because
过去的日子为什么不复返了?我们怎样丢掉了我们整个社会的共同愿景?
为什么没人能在给我们一个目的,我们朝着它一起奋斗了?这事好像离我们远去了
where did that go where did we lose a shared Vision why can't somebody put a flag in the ground and say this is where we're headed that seems to be gone
这是个复杂的问题.我觉得是我们从根本上接受了上帝已死的结果
yeah well that's a complicated question you know I mean I would say that's the consequence in the most fundamental sense of uh of of the death of God in the most fundamental way
这是我们放弃了某种高阶的统一
it's the death of it's the death of a sense of higher order Unity
你问别人你想要什么?这也是一个很难回答的问题
it's also a very complicated question if you ask someone what do you want?
如果你问你的妻子,你想要什么?你大概率会让她哑口无言
if you could ask your wife that what do you want you'll probably freeze her into immobility
因为这很像问你,请用一段话概括,解释你想要过什么样的人生一样.
because it it's really like asking how do you want all of your life to go please summarize
人生太长了,一段话真的说不下
and one of the things yeah well it's it's a lot you know and
你作为一个精通认知行为的肯定熟悉另一种问这种问题的方式,就是问很多小问题
one of the ways that you can deal with that which you undoubtedly know as a as a as someone who's conversant with cognitive behavioral techniques is you can ask people more micro questions too about what they want
我们之前在讨论约会的时候,已经说了该如何做了.
我们说了你想要什么时间吃饭?我们只讨论了晚餐,我们还可以讨论早餐,午餐.
so you might say well well we did that on The Dating front already right we talked about that we talked about how you might think about how you want your meal times to go
你还在还其它关键的区域问你自己类似的问题.
如果你得到了你想要的教育,你会变成什么样呢?
and then you and there are other micro domains that are very crucial that you can also consider it's like so you could ask yourself well if you could have the education you wanted what would that look like
如果你走在自己想象中的职业道路,你会是什么样呢?
虽然你没有,但想想又不会怎么样,最起码能激励一下吧
if you were on if you had the job career track that would motivate you just hypothetically what might that look like
先弄出一个计划,不管这个计划有多烂.有总比没有好
sketch out a bad plan
你也可以问自己,如果你有一些朋友,你想....?不,先问你你想要朋友吗?
如果你想要的话,多少呢?如果你想要朋友,且合适的数量,你每周想他们一起花多少时间呢?
if you had some friends do you well first do you want some friends and if so how many and and if you had friends and the right number how much time per week would you like to spend with them
还可以问,如果你在工作,家庭责任以外还有一些时间的话,你想在这些空余时间干什么你特别感兴趣的呢?
and if you had some time outside of work and familial responsibilities what might you like to do with your time that you would really like to do and
这些问题都是很真实的问题
the thing about these questions is that they're they're real questions
有一句马太福音是这样说的,因为凡祈求的，就得到;寻找的,就找到;敲门的,就为他开门.
you know there's this   gospel statement that if you knock the door will open and that if you ask you will receive and if you search you'll find if you seek you'll find
无信的人们某种程度上把这句话当成了超市卖的祝福卡片上的短语一样.
认为你只要要了某事,某事就会发生.
不是这样的,这句话的意思不是这样的
and people who are faithless in some sense think about it as kind of a Hallmark greeting card approach to the world it's just well you just ask for things and they appear it's like no that isn't what any of that means
它的真实意思是,你想要的东西并不会自主出现,除非你开始追求它.
你并不会追求它,除非你自己知道自己想要什么.
Nothing  that you want will manifest itself unless you aim for it and you won't aim for it unless you know what it is.
你不知道你想要什么直到你问自己这个问题
You won't know what it is unless you ask yourself
你会问自己为什么自己从来没有问过自己这个问题呢?
也许答案是从来没有人给你解答这个问题到你需要的程度.
光这个没有跟你解答问题到你需要的程度的事实,这就已经是一个很严肃的问题了
and then you might say well why don't you ask yourself and the answer is well maybe no one ever explained to you that you needed to which is a crucial issue.
也许自己本身就不信任自己.你会想如果我让我自己知道我到底想要什么
and maybe you dont also trust yourself.Because you might think if i let myself know what i wanted.
从过往经验来看,我为了失败可谓是做了一切的功夫.
所以我宁愿让我自己对本身不清不楚,这样我才不会让自己在重要的事上失败.
Given  my bloody track record,i would do everything i could to screw it up.So i'll just keep myself opqque to myself sothat i dont't fail at something that's truly important.
这样我就可以一直自我嘲弄的说,我没有成功是因为我没有努力过,如果我努力了,那么我早就成功了.
I can alwa ys regale with myself with the diea that well i didn't succeed but i didn't really try hard.
但如果你让自己知道了你想要什么,然后你努力了.
你也就为后续的失败满足了前置条件.
whereas if you let yourself know what you want and then you try,you also set the precondition for failures.
这的确是有风险的.但如果不承担这个风险的话,你就不知道你想要什么
it's risky but the alternative is well you don't know what you want
你可以尝试尝试冥想,想象如果你有了你想要的东西,
且这个世界构成的物质不会因为我得到了我想要和需要的东西而导致整个星球在末日中爆炸,
那会是怎样的风景呢?
o it is a meditative practice like okay if I could have what I wanted imagine the world was constituted so that the entire planet wouldn't explode in an apocalypse if I got what I needed and wanted yeah right it's like what would that be
那会是怎样的(打断施法) .请问这是认知上的训练吗.额 我不想要专业术语.这是思维上的锻炼?还是情感上的锻炼
you know what kinda
is this a cognitive well I don't want to use jargon is this a thought exercise or is this a feeling exercise
这是我观察整个美国得到的结论.我以为我成为学校副校长之后我会感觉不同
because here's what I'm seeing across the country I thought it would feel different when I finally got that associate Vice President Job.
我以为我买了一辆车后,我会感到满足
我以为我和她去约会后,我会感到满足
I thought I would feel a certain way when I got a car I thought if I could just get to her to date me I would feel a certain way and
人们在很快的意识到"我支持的政治人物赢了的话,我会感到满足"这句话不是真的
and people are are realizing in Rapid fashion I thought if my politician won I would suddenly feel a certain way
我曾经在几年前在法庭,对我的一个学生做不利于他的证词.他做了一些很糟糕的事情
here's a great I  I I testified in a court case against somebody years ago a former student of mine um got into some significant some really terrible things
最后他要在监狱进行长期的处罚.第二天早晨,我醒来后读法官写的东西,里面引用了我的一些话.
突然之间,我感到胃部恶心干呕.我问了我的一个心理学教授朋友,我说我感到恶心.她对我说,这里没人是成功者
um and he got a long jail sentence and the next morning I woke up and I read what the judge had written and in the sentencing and I he the judge used some of my words and I remember feeling sick to my stomach and I called the mentor of mine a psychology friend uh professor of mine and asked her I said man I feel gross and she said John nobody wins here and
我当初以为,当正义被执行之后,我会感到满足.
我当初只是在认知上知道他会进监狱,但我从情感上还不知道该如何应对.
到底该如何感受呢,当大家都是失败者的时候.有人的生命已经被毁灭了,有人的生命正在被毁灭
I had this perception that I was going to feel a certain way when Justice was done and the right thing happened and I realized man I had thought this through cognitively but I had not managed how are you going to actually feel because nobody wins somebody's life is ruined over here somebody's life is still ruined over here
我认为我们需要...我不知道让我...你在这方面应该比我拥有更多的智慧.
但是我觉得那个认知上的训练的确会有帮助,但更重要的是,坐下来,问自己,如果自己把车买了,我认为我5天之后会感受会是什么呢?
I think we have to I don't know let me uh you're you're infinitely um you've got infinitely more wisdom than I do on this but I find that the cognitive exercise is helpful but it really is important to sit down and say okay how are you gonna feel five days after you've bought this car that you
think you have to have well okay so the first thing is is that the probability that you'll be happy
首先因为你完成了一件事情,而感到开心的概率在永恒角度上是无限迫近于零的
okay so the first thing is is that the probability that you'll be happy because you've accomplished something in any permanent sense is virtually zero
你说的太对了
我这句话的根据是,因为正向感情不是用于在这方面上的.
正向感情是你在不断朝着一个有意义目标前行的副产物
and the reason yes thank you for saying that well the reason for that is that isn't what positive emotion is for positive emotion is to indicate that you're making progress towards a valued
goal
正向感情是途中的风景线,不是终点线的奖励品.N now that's the driver right not not the Finish Line
是的,它们之间在药理学上是分开的,因为完成某事后的满足感会让你平静下来,让你不在继续之前的行为
exactly well and that's actually pharmacologically separate right,because a satiation reward which would be the accomplishment of something calms you and stops that program from running
你说,成为副校长是你的当初的目标.当你实现这个目标的时候,你整个追寻这个目标的程序就到此为止了
so for example once you've become vice president if that was your goal then the whole pursuing vice president program comes to a halt.
它留下的问题是,你现在没有了目标,也留给你了空缺,你需要来填补
now the problem with that is it leaves you without a goal and it also leaves empty space which you immediately have to fill and
所以人们在完成目标反而会感到焦虑,因为它们不知道接下来要干什么
它们怀念那个奋斗的感觉,只因不知道现在要追求什么
so often people feel disquiet because now they don't know what to do and they miss that rush because they're no longer pursuing something and
一个很重要的知识就是,正向情感是在追求一个有价值的目标中获得的.
那什么是最有价值的目标呢.这个问题就很形而上学且理论的了.
so it's very important to know that positive emotion is experienced in relationship to a valued goal and then the question becomes well
what's the most valuable goal to pursue and that's really a metaphysical and a theological question
关于情感的运行机制,想象你和你的妻子就约会的内容商讨,你,们在搭建一个共同愿景
in terms of the mechanics of feeling so imagine that you're negotiating the structure of a date with your wife and you're developing a shared vision and
你说每周三一次.我们要出去吃饭,你来定餐馆,你来做安排,而我负责打扮
.我们要去看场电影,而你负责选看哪部.然后我们去浪漫的幽会.
so you say well on Wednesday nights once a week we're going to go for dinner and maybe you specify the restaurant and you're going to make the arrangements and I'm going to get dressed up and then we're going to go see a movie and you're going to pick the movie and and then we're going to have a romantic interlude afterwards .
我们先跑一遍这个流程,观察事情的发展.
接下来的步骤就是如实的叙述你的观点,并观察你们的身体怎么在情感的层面上共鸣
and we'll.we'll run that and see how it goes and then what you want to do is you want to picture that and you want to watch how your body reacts on the emotional level
这需要两者之间的诚实.你可能觉得这次去的那家餐馆你不喜欢,有点贵.
我和服务员有点纠纷,我不认为我会在那开心.你把你的这些感受告诉你的伴侣
and and that's a that's a bit of honesty it's right and you can see well if we went to this restaurant oh I don't really like that restaurant I think it's kind of expensive I had a bad time with waiters I don't think I'd be happy there then you say those things to your partner
你说,我思考了下,这些是我想出来的上次没做好的地方,
它们有可能有不对的地方,我想听听你的想法,因为我们想把这件事搞对
you say well I'm thinking this through I'm imagining it and here's the objections that are coming up maybe they're wrong maybe I've got this wrong but I'd like to hear your input because you know we want to get this right
我们应该重新评估下我对餐厅的感受吗?我们应该换一家餐厅吗?这应该是一个值得讨论的问题,因为你在意这个问题了
也许你对这个餐厅的看法有些许问题了,也许你觉得你cheap,你觉得自己没有配的上这餐厅的衣服所以你不想去.
你不知道的问题才值得讨论啊
should we reevaluate my feelings about the restaurant or should we think about a different restaurant and that should be a questionn because you don't know maybe you're just stupid about the restaurant or you're cheap or you're afraid to go there because you don't have the right clothes I mean you don't know
如果你想和你的伴侣在情感上保持一致,你们一起开发一种愿景.
你用你的情感去理解你们的愿景.这如同你去电影院看电影,你和电影里的人物感情上共鸣一样,以他们的角度沉浸在剧情之中
ut if you want to get your feelings in line you develop the vision and then you you you apprehend the
vision with your feelings it's kind of what you do when you go to a movie and you fall into the fantasy of the character you know you embody all the emotions and you evaluate it that way
还有一个关于你目标导向方法的问题就是,我认为大家需要做计划,愿景的同时,与出来的结果保持一定的距离.
因为做出来的目标是需要经常更新,修正的,不要认准就不放了
and so and and the other problem with that more goal directed approach that you described is like I think people should plan and they should develop a vision you have to develop the vision and then be somewhat detached from it because it needs to be updated right and modified and hold it Loosely
yeyeye,松散地握住你的计划,因为你只是一个会出错的人,也许一会能想出一个更好的计划.
但你不会每分每秒都会想出一个更好的计划,因为这样只会让你疯狂,但偶尔还是会有好点子的
yeah yeah you hold it Loosely yeah that's right because you're fallible and maybe you can come up with a better plan not every minute because you'll drive yourself mad that way but but now and then
当我还是一个年轻的高校教师的时候,我一直成为校长.当我坐到管理层的时候,
我意识到我不想要那样的人生,我不想一年365天24小时随叫随到,我不想和政治沾边,我不想去拉赞助.我不想要那样的生活
or I I I I I was obsessed as a young higher education professional with becoming a college President until I sat down at the senior leadership table and I realized I I want that life I don't want I don't want that that life I don't want 24 7 365 and the politics I don't want it asking for money I don't want that life
我当初没有其它的计划,我不知道我还可能干什么.你说对了,那时我倍感焦虑,因为我毫无头绪.只因我把终点线当成了目标
I didn't have I didn't have a backup plan I didn't know what to do I was right like you nailed it I was completely rudderless because I'd made the finish line the the goal
回到最初的话题,我认为在现在社会里知道自己是谁,以及知道我想成为什么样的人还是很重要的,这样才能设置目标
going all the way back full circle to the how you open the conversation I think that becomes really important to lay out an identity and reverse engineer who do I want to be who do I want to become and the goals end up
在过去的日子里,读一个phd就单纯的是继续学习的一部分,我准备一脚踏入泥潭了.
you know it's like the old days um when you went to grad school a PhD was simply a a it was a a high five on a journey of of continued learning I'm gonna continue going down this rabbit hole and
而现在phd就像是旅途的终点,当人们跨过这个终点的时候,他们就说自己是受过教育的人.
他们这种说话,就像一个跑完/走完马拉松的人认为他们身体无疾病一样now it's become a destination and people walk out and announce themself as educated because I've I've crossed this Finish Line just because you get across a you run a marathon or walking Marathon it doesn't mean you're fit right doesn't mean you're healthy well
我们之前讨论了目标的必须性.而目标有高低之分,你需要高阶目标因为它完善你.
而成为一个学校校长的确是一个高阶目标,而没有目标就是躺在床上,吃薯片
well we did we talked about the necessity of goals and so there's higher order goals and and you need the higher order goals because they integrate you and a goal of becoming a college President is a higher order goal then no goal at all in just sitting in your bed and eating Cheetos right
有计划总比没计划好,但这也是事情开始变得严肃和影响重大起来
it's a better plan than no plan at all but but and this is where things become profound and serious and
我会说在宗教方面上,计划也是严肃,影响重大的问题.
I would say even in in a religious sense
因为宗教的定义某种程度上就是关于什么是严肃的和影响重大的
because what's religious is about what's profound and serious in some sense by definition
所以当你问我要是谁的时候?你也许说,我要成为学校校长,我想要这辆车,我想要这个房子.
这些都是你这个人想要的东西,但是都是不同阶段的你想要的
so you might say well who should I be and you might think well I should be the college President I should have this car I should have this house those are all very particularized versions of yourself
它们的问题是它们已经实体化和已经不可变了,不可有进展了
and the problem with them is is that their concrete and final actualities and not processes and
我要说一个好的愿景,一个高阶愿景.我觉得我们的文化在这上面建立起来的.就是我要成为正视问题,处理问题的人
so here's a good Vision that's a high order vision and I think it's the vision that our whole culture is founded on I should be the person who genuinely confronts the problems and challenges that confront me in my life
这是一种积极和自愿参与的态度
so that's that's a that's an attitude of active and voluntary engagement right
这是一种自我认同.是的,这也是自我认同的一个过程.我要做个不逃避问题的人,我要做个直面解决问题的人
I'm gonna that's an identity yeah yeah and yeah that that's a nice it's an identity of process as well it's like I'm going to be someone who doesn't shy away from the challenges of life yes okay and I'm a guy who confronts it right right and
这是圣乔治和恶龙的故事.这是向好转变的前置要求.
只有你知道问题,恶龙,出现在哪里,以及你自愿的面对它,你才能成长
so that's Saint George and the Dragon and that's that's a precondition for therapeutic transformation because in order for you to improve you have to identify the problem the dragon and you have to be willing to face it voluntarily
所以你说我要尽我可能的去培养我的勇气,来助我自愿地直面生活的问题.这是我想成为的人
and so you say to yourself I'm going to do what I can to develop the courage to confront the problems in my life voluntarily that's who I want to be.
还有一点就是,如果你不愿意讲出事实的话,你不可能直面解决问题.
我必须诚实的说出我面前的问题是什么,我说明我的想法,感觉是什么.我也必须自愿去做这方面的沟通
then another element of that is oh I can't do that without telling the truth I have to be willing to see what's in front of me and I have to be willing to admit to myself what I think and feel and I have to be willing to communicate that and
你可以说这些特质让你的目标原初,典型,完美
you could say well that makes you that makes your goal something like to think about it archetypally
你之前提到的荣格的方法,让你成为一个说真话的英雄
you talked about jungian approaches earlier is that that makes you into a truth-telling hero
低阶目标更像是,我可以成为校长吗,我可以在事业上成功吗?我能有幸福的婚姻吗?
and then maybe underneath that it's like well could I become College president could I be successful in my business could I be successful in my marriage
这些都是不错的目标,但他们都太具体了.高阶目标更像是一个指导你的方法,而不是一个最终的状态
it's like that's all well and good and those are more concretized goals but the the highest order goal has to be something like an approach rather than a final state
因为方法论永远不是中止.是的.你可以说我想成为一个倾听我妻子的人.你永远不会完成这个目标.
right because you might say the approach never ends that's right well and you can say to yourself I want to be the guy who listens to my wife yeah okay so you're never gonna you're never gonna finalize that right
因为你一辈子都要继续做下去.这很有帮助,因为你永远没法满足这个目标,所以你永不会内心有空缺,因为你每天都可以做
because you're doing that all the time and that's also really useful because you don't hit the target and then and then find yourself left with nothing because you can do that every day
我想做一个倾听孩子发言的人,我想做一个对朋友用心的人,我想做一个说出我真心所想且发言谨慎用心的人
I want to be the guy who listens to my kids I want to be the guy who pays attention to my friends and I want to be the guy who speaks my mind carefully and judiciously
你可以在何时何地都做到这些
it's like you can bring that anywhere man
你在这讨论方法论和目标的区别.and you're you're and you're talking you're talking about the difference there that approach
让我用你的例子来说明.我想做我妻子的后盾.这是我的自我认知.为了称的上这个认知,我要有一系列的目标
let's use your example I'm a I want to be a guy who's a good Steward of my wife.,I want to be that's that's my identity ,and that means I'm gonna have to backfill it with some goals
我们要一周至少畅聊一次,我不会像修发动机一样就维修她,
我不会帮她向对待小婴儿那样解决她的问题,我只是倾听,我承诺我在倾听的时候保持安静
we're gonna meet once a week and I'm not gonna try to fix her like she's a car engine I'm not gonna try to solve her problems with her as though she's infantile I'm gonna just listen and I'm gonna commit to being quiet and .
当她说她和老板有矛盾的时候,我不会告诉她她需要和老板说清楚.
so when she says I'm really struggling with my boss at work.I'm not going to jump in with well you know you should probably tell him
我的存在只是为了倾听.但在倾听的同时,我也想对我妻子了解得更多.
她这一个季度过得怎么样,和上一个季度有什么不同,下个季度会有什么变化呢
I'm just gonna I'm just gonna listen right but listen over time I begin I really look forward to learning more about my wife and what she's experiencing in this season and it's different than last season it's going to be different in the new season
Esther Perel说过成年人的一生中会遇到4,5个爱人.
如果你投入的话,这4,5个爱人都是同一个人的不同阶段
I think it was uh Esther perel who said if most adults have four  five great loves in their lifetime and if you work really really hard it's with the same person and you become part of their journey and
我已经迫不及待的想知道她最近在读什么,她最近怎么样了,以及我如何在新的季节成为一个更好的伴侣
and now I can't wait to hear about what my wife's been reading who she's becoming and how I can best be a be a partner to her in this new season whatever it is
不要一直沉迷在过去约会时的欢愉.一直沉迷过于只是浪费时间.让我们一起向前走
it's not constantly trying to get back to remember how much fun we have and we were dating man .what a waste of a life.let's go this way right let's move forward
Jordan麻烦你告诉我,我对掌握和承认现实这个概念的理解对不对
tell me if I'm if I'm on the right track here that idea of owning acknowledging reality
我不想长胖,但我比过去涨了15kg.
我不是有意的,但是我在过去的15年内一直做着我不喜欢的中层管理.
我讨厌我生活的一成不变,但我每天还是会去上班
I didn't mean to but I'm looking in the mirror and I've gained 100 pounds I didn't mean to I it wasn't my intention but now I've spent 15 years in a middle manager job and I hate my life I hate going to work every day
我认为,我们没有对人生事务的舍断离的能力.
而这个能力也是心理功能上很重要的一部分.这好像是Ernest Becker还是yolom的研究方向
I think we do not have the skill set for one of the most important psychological functions that we just we just extract we just just took it out of life right and I think it's it's Ernest Becker's work and yolom's work
我认为我们也丢失了自省(grief)的能力,不管是个人层面还是集体.
I think we don't have uh any sort of um ability to grieve privately or as a group we've lost a skill set of grief and
我们无法正视现实,因为当我们看向自身的时候,我们不知道要干什么
so we can't acknowledge reality because we don't know what to do when we look in the mirror and
当我看向自身的时候,我没有成为我期待的那个人.
我刚才不想对我的孩子发火,但是我还是发了.我知道自己不应该吃那个甜点,但是我还是吃了
say I didn't measure up to who I wanted to be,I didn't mean to yell at my kid and I did,I didn't mean to get another dessert and I did
因为我们不知道如何自省,所以我们只能放纵欲望和怒火,然后用语言表达出来.we can't deal with that grief and so we Blow by it and say
快把所有的甜品放到我的面前
and say you keep putting desserts in front of me
xxx(代入自己的名字)!如果你好好整理的话,那我还会吼你?你以为我想吼你?!!!!
or if you had just picked up your trike six-year-old I wouldn't have yelled at you.
我们只是在对外释放我们长久积攒出来的,对自己和对世界的怨恨,
因为我们不知道该如何处理理想和现实的差距
we just Outsource our dysfunction everywhere because we can't sit in that gap between what we wanted and our reality
你说了好多事啊
all right so a couple of things there
有一点是,你说,你在与你妻子中改变生活方式的尝试中,找到了自我的认知
you talked about finding yourself on the adventure of transformation with your wife
现在男性感觉,当他们的妻子告诉他们问题的时候,他们有种强迫性的责任感来给她们一个解决方法
now often men feel compelled obligated to generate a solution to the problems that their wives bring them
女性的确更能受到负面情绪的影响,也因为如此,她们也更愿意提出问题
and it is the case because women feel more negative emotion that they are more likely to bring up problems
这也是70%的离婚都是女性提出来的,因为她们更容易感受到负面情绪.
所以当婚姻摇摇欲坠的时候,女性比男性更早的感到痛苦,也更多的感到更多的痛苦,这也导致她们受到更多的负面情绪
.她们为什么更受负面情绪的影响,因为她们更加敏感.为什么她们更加敏感,因为她们要照顾婴儿
that's why 70 percent of divorces by the way are initiated by women it's because they feel more negative emotions so if the relationship is shaky they're going to suffer for it more and they probably feel more negative emotion
这个话题我们先放在一边
and so anyways we can put that aside now it
的确你应该帮助你的妻子解决她的问题.也许她也的确是在寻求你的帮助
now it might be that you should help your wife solve her problems and maybe she's coming to you for that
但是!有一点你得理解
,你可以把自己当成接诊医生(接诊医生起码也得先听患者自述,再上仪器,再给方案吧),
你觉得你知道她的问题是什么吗?
but one thing you need to understand and you might understand this as a diagnostician is well do you know what the hell her problem is and
大概率上是你不知道,因为她自己都不知道她的问题是啥,你又怎么会呢?
the answer is well probably not because she doesn't even know
为什么她愿意坐下来和你讨论她的问题呢?因为她也想知道她的问题到底是什么
so why does she want to sit down and tell you about her problems and the answer is because she wants to find out what her bloody problems are and
Carl Rogers说如果你倾听别人说话的话,他们经常就是说着说着就自己把问题解决了
你在话疗中经常内看到
so you see this very often in therapy you know when Carl Rogers made a lot of this he said you know if you just listen to people they'll often solve most of their problems themselves and
所以有人向你说最近不开心的时候,你可以说最近有啥事困扰着你吗?
so somebody comes in and they say well I'm really upset.and you say well what's on your mind now
最有趣的一点就是,来话疗的人们,他们都通常没有其它人来让他们诉说自己的问题
what's so interesting about that is often the people who are in therapy have absolutely no one to tell their problems to
所以我觉得Rogerian argument(Carl Rogers提出的)的魔法在于倾听,
以及我们一直没有提到的一点,他在尽最大的可能去爱坐在他面前的人.
you know like I think I think the rogerian magic though was listening and he brought that other that other side of the equation that we we leave out he listened and he genuinely did his best to love the person in front of him yeah
对的,不要从批判的角度看别人
well okay so not sit in Judgment of that person
所以当我妻子向我倾诉的时候,与其告诉她你应该怎么做,还不如告诉她,你爱她,让我们在情感上连接,不要尝试解决问题
so my wife says Hey I'm going through this .I I instantly go well you know you should instead of sitting back and going I love this person tell me,let's connect not let's solve right
这的确是个很好的思维方式.
这也是实现这个高阶目标,即你和你的妻子过者幸福的生活,的一部分.
so so you you'd hope that's your mindset and this would be part of establishing that high order goal is imagine you would like your wife and you to have a good life and
所以当你倾听她的时候,你要记住你们想过上幸福的生活,要怀着这种想法来回应她
so when you're listening to her that's uppermost in your mind we're trying to have a good life ,here okay so what's your problem well
如果你曾以therapeutically的方式倾听别人过的话,你会发现他们都是从各个角度描述一个问题的片面
well if you're listening to someone therapeutically they're going to scatter shot the problem
他们会说,有可能是这里的问题,有可能是那里,可能是这个,可能是那个,可能和过去有影响
they're going to say well it might be this and it might be this and it might be this it might have something to do with the past and it might be this and
当他们在尝试描述真正的问题的时候,一般都是描述的很一团乱
it's it's quite a mess as they try to calibrate the real problem
所以你必须倾听所有他说的东西.
但你又常常注意到,当他说出大部分猜想的时候,他又会自己把自己的猜想给否决掉
and you have to listen to all that and what you'll find is that the person will dispense with most of those hypotheses themselves as soon as they utter them
他们会想这是我的问题,但想了想后,又发现不怎么对
they'll think well here's my problem no that's not exactly right and
这样刚才那个想法可以弃置不管了
so now that's off the table
他们会说也许这是我的问题,的确有些依据支撑我这个观点.然后说,好像也不是
and they'll say well it might be this and here's some reasons for thinking that but no it's probably not that and
这样你会发现问题的范围正在逐渐缩小
so what you'll find is the problem space will clear now
Roger也指出了,在倾听的时候问问题也是很有帮助的.
问题可以像,我这段话我没有听懂,你现在说的好像和你10分钟前说的相互矛盾了
Rogers also pointed out and this is very useful is that one of the things you can do when you're listening apart from asking questions which might be well  I don't quite understand what you meant by that or you said something 10 minutes ago and it seems to contradict what you just said now
这些都是有帮助的问题
which are just helpful questions
还有一点你可以做的就是总结
the other thing you can do is summarize and
你可以说,我听了10,15分钟,这是我对你刚才说的理解,你觉得我理解的对吗?
you can say well I've been listening for 10 minutes or 15 minutes and it seems to me that this is what you said is that right and
有两个原因大家喜欢听你总结.一是,你把复杂的信息总结成了精华,这对大家真的很有帮助
that people really like that for for two reasons a is one is you compact all that searching into the gist and that's a gift you can give someone
如果你的总结正是他所表达的意思,那他就知道你是真真正正认真的在听他的发言
and then also if you hit the target if you say yeah that's exactly what I meant then they know full well that you've really been listening
如果你是个男性,你在听这场对话,你想知道当听妻子阐述她问题的时候,你到底该怎么做呢?
and so if you can if you're a man and you're listening to this and you want to know how to deal with your wife when she's presenting you with problems .
第一件事就是,退后一步,对自己说,她有可能要说很久才能把问题说完,所以耐下心来,倾听就好了
.你可以总结,你可以问问题,但关键就是找到到底是什么问题在困扰她
The first thing is is step back a bit and say look she probably has to go through the whole problem set and try not to take that personally just listen and and and you can summarize and you can ask questions but mostly you want to find out well what the hell is the problem
也许你想跳过这一切,快进到解决办法.你有很多理由做这些.here now you might want to LEAP to a solution for for a bunch of reasons
第一个就是展示你有一个解决方案
one is well to show that you have a solution
第二点就是展示你比你妻子更聪明.这是个很糟糕的想法
two is to show you're smarter than your wife which is very bad idea
第三点就是你想让她闭嘴,这样你就不需要坐在这听她讲话了.这也是个很糟糕的想法
the third is to shut her up so that you don't have to sit there and listen and that's also a really bad idea
因为你永远没法让任何一个人对一个问题上闭上嘴.
因为这个问题是个真实的问题,这个问题不会自己解决
because you can't shut anybody up about an actual problem right that just doesn't work because it's an actual problem it's not going to
go away
而如果她只是来和你情感上连接的,她不是在向你寻求答案.
而你让她闭嘴的行为,你在给她一种明显的,我不在意你,我不想和你情感上连接的态度
or if she's coming to you to connect and she's not looking for your solution she just wants to connect and this is the tool set that she has when you shut her up you're giving a much more existential I don't value you right I don't want to connect with you um and
出现这个事情的时候,说明你们的关系正处于危机当中
that's a much bigger um I think that's a much more crisis or
your relationship's in a mess at that point yeah
是的,这种情况在每周90分钟的谈话中也会出现,因为你们需要倾听别人说话.你们需要那么长的时间来沟通交流谈心
well that yes exactly well and you'll find too with this 90 minutes a week that you have to listen to each other is that in some sense you need that amount of time to clear the air
事实就是,当人生不断前行.各种各样的麻烦(小型的恶龙)在不断的显现出来.
事情和以前不一样了,汽车需要维修,孩子遇到了麻烦,浴室下水道出现了问题,存款慢慢见底,等等.
有数不尽的琐事在不断的出现
because you can imagine that as you move through life Little Dragons make themselves manifest all the time because things change the car needs maintenance there's a problem with the kid there's something wrong with the bathroom sink um we don't have quite enough money in the checking account you know there's a hundred little niggling demons that pop up constantly
如果房子里存在着一堆的杂事没有处理的话,会很难创建一个营造愉快亲密关系的温床.
伴侣之间的沟通交流才是使这些杂事缩小,以至消失
and it's very difficult to establish the preconditions for joyful intimacy when there's a nest of micro dragons swarming all over the house and you have to talk those through in order to keep them small and to make them go away
如果你把这件事当成经常要做的事的话,
也许你们每周的沟通就可以不仅限于分享问题,而是可以去找乐子了
and if you do that with some degree of programmatic regularity then you do have the possibility that you'll get beyond the mere sharing of problems then you can have some fun then you can play
我想说两点.yes but I think uh two things one
一是给观众的建议
One here a helpful tip for the listeners here
我觉得我婚姻有很好的一点就是,当我的妻子开始和我分享的时候,我一般会打断一下,问她,你在想和我找到问题的答案还是想和我谈心?there's been fantastic in my marriage is when my wife sits down and begins to talk I'll often stop at the very beginning and say are you asking me for a solution or are you looking to just tell me are you looking to connect and
这通常给谈话定下了方向,我知道她想从我这得到什么
that is often frames the conversation in a way that I know where I what what she's asking from me
这的确会在一开始显得不浪漫,这就像把搓澡放进日历一样,几秒钟的尴尬,但改变了接下来一周,一个月的走向
and it seems very unromantic at first but man on the back end it saves so it's just ike putting sex on the calendar right it just a couple of seconds of awkward changes the trajectory of your entire week and month
我也认为男人或多或少的不了解我们提供的关系价值,所以我们认为我们的价值只能在提供某事的解决方案中体现出来
I also think that men have rightly or wrongly we found ourselves we don't understand our relational value and so we think our value can only be found in offering a solution to something
我觉得我们提供的关系价值,也是一种深层次的亲密,也是一种深层次的连接.
and there's a deeper intimacy there's a deeper connection um
我妻子重视我仅仅因为我是她的丈夫
my wife values me simply because I am her husband
我的确帮助提供了东西.我的确做了一些事情,而这些事情的确有些作用.
I help provide and yes I've I you know can do all these other things there's utility there
但我必须看出我的价值,不仅限于给一个没我那么强,没我那么聪明的人答案.
有些时候,我可以给我妻子最好的就是陪伴
but I have to see myself as having more value than giving a person less with less power or less smarts than me an answer
我们得克服,因为无能为力,只能聆听,而产生的不安.
我们得克服,因为我们没办法给帮助而产生的,无能感.
and we have to get underneath that discomfort of I I'm out of my depths here I don't know what to do other than just listen and I feel useless I feel like I've lost utility right yeah well
我认为你这个只倾听的说法就一点不足.就是倾听真的是很难做到的一件事
I think the problem with that formulation is the idea of just listening it's really hard to listen
我喜欢这个说法
and there's almost I like that I like that
因为你的倾听给了别人一个可以思考的机会,没有比这更有帮助,更有改造作用的事情了
well there's almost nothing you can do that's more transformative to that than that and the reason for that is that just listening gives the other person an opportunity to just think
你可能想知道他们在思考的时候到底在干什么
and so then you might say well what are they doing when they're thinking and
他们在问自己问题,在寻找启发,在整理已有的信息来决定前进的最好道路,他们在尝试发展和更新他们的人生愿景
and here's what they're doing is they're asking themselves questions and looking for a revelation they're trying to sort through information so that they can determine the best pathway forward and they're trying to update and develop their vision for their life
你在真正实践之前,用抽象思维考虑种种的可能性
and you do that in abstraction to test out the possibilities before you implement them and
所以当你在倾听别人的时候,你也给了别人思考的空间
so if you give people space to think which is exactly what you're doing when you're listening
他们才可以尝试回顾自己的言行举止,所思所想,知道哪个才是真正的自己.所以倾听不仅仅只是倾听.
then they try out different versions of themselves so they can experiment with finding the best fit and so there's
nothing just about listening
所以我认为,除了用语言谨慎地,准确地,如实地表达你的想法外,没有比倾听更难的事情了it's I think apart from speaking accurately and carefully and truthfully there isn't anything more difficult that you can do than to listen
身为一个心理医师,我最喜欢的一点就是,这一点也对我不当心理医师后的生涯也很有帮助,
就是如果你真正的倾听别人的话,他们会告诉你所有的事
and one of the things I loved about being a therapist and it's been very useful to me in my post therapy career as well is that if you actually listen to people they will tell you everything
他们对有人倾听他们感到太开心了,以至于你都很承受他们的热情.
and then they're so interesting you can hardly stand them
现在轮到我参访你了,那你能给这些22-27岁这些正准备进入社会的男听众一些能让他们锻炼倾听的一些实用建议吗?
从而让他们对话中不再直奔解决方法.so give me um and by proxy The Listener give a 22 to 27 year old man trying to make his way in the world what is one or two or three things I I guess I'm turning the interview around on you  now what's a couple of practical skills that I can do to lean into listening to practice listening and stop trying to rush to a solution
不再因为不安而企图结束对话.try to get out of a a conversation because I'm uncomfortable
我从来没锻炼过倾听,我从来没见过我的父亲,爷爷做过.他们只是吼出命令来,然后去看比赛
I don't have the skill set I never saw my dad do it my granddad never did it they just they just barked orders and watched the game
我想尝试一些比电视换台和对着电视里打橄榄球的运动员大喊无限难的举动
I'm trying to do something that is infinitely more difficult than just flipping channels and yelling at the Packers game
我可以做什么来锻炼呢? what what's a couple of things I can practice well
第一点就是,你的反应并非毫无价值.
I would say first is have some faith in your own reactions not as solutions to the problem but as points of inquiry
举例说明的话,就是当我们讨论的时候,问题不断的浮现于我的脑海,我也很乐意把这些问题一一讨论
so for example when we're talking questions arise in the  and topics pop up and I'm willing to put them on the table
这些问题出现的原因就是我在意你说的内容.听你说,我也有了自己的想法.
and the reason they they pop up is because I'm attending to what you say and that's generating some thoughts in my mind
而你能做的就是问出你的这些问题
and one of the great things you can do with people is ask them questions
问问题有什么难的
I mean there is nothing
我觉得这个问题和我们之前讨论的交友和建立关系有关
and this goes back to the the issue of say making friends or establishing relationships
人们最想要的莫过于被注意
这也是为什么广告行业投了那么多的钱就为了获得人们的注意力
there's nothing that people want more than to be attended to that's why advertisers spend so much money trying to Garner attention
这也是社交平台花了那么多的钱就为了获得人们的注意力
that's why social media companies spend so much money garnering people's attention
注意力才是最基础的金钱啊
attention is the fundamental currency
所以人们喜欢被注意到
and so people love to be attended to and
所以抛弃你只是在倾听这个观点吧
so you dispense with the idea that you're just listening
你是在观察别人的同时,同时倾听.
is you're watching the other person and you're listening
然后你可以把部分注意力放在自己身上,观察倾听自己.
因为你会发现一旦你把注意里放在对话中,你就立马不会为你接下来要说什么而烦恼,不会为你表现如何而烦恼.
这些放在自己身上的注意力会让你太注意自己在别人眼中的形象,让你难受和尴尬
and then you're attending to yourself and watching and listening because you'll see that as you focus on the conversation and don't worry about what you're going to say next or how you appear which makes you self-conscious and miserable and awkward instantly.
你把注意力集中在谈话上,你观察谈话中到底说了什么,
当你有问题的时候,你就可以说,我有一个问题you pay attention to the conversation and
then you watch what happens inside and
this question comes up and you say well I have this question
你不会知道你问题的答案除非你深刻地参与进这场对话中.
你要做的就是打断对话,把问题说出了.
说我没怎么理解你刚才说了什么,或者说我有另一种角度看这个问题的解释,你觉得怎么样.
and you don't evaluate the question you you know not if you're deeply engaged in the conversation you just lay it out and you you pull you draw the person out and you see well I don't quite understand what you said there or it seems to me that this is a different way of looking at it ,what do you think of that.
你问的问题必须得是从谈话中得到的问题
the questions have to be honest but
如果你能集中注意在一场对话中,然后问出真心的问题,你就已经具备了90%的对话能力
but if you if you pay focused attention and you ask genuine questions you've got like 90 percent of social skill nailed
我喜欢你之前提到的小恶龙的说话,我要继续沿用那个话题
and you get below you get below I love what you said about the Little Dragons I might I might steal that down the road
你看今天的新闻了吗?我们最近从银行里取了太多的钱了
did you see what was on the news today or hey we're overdrawn on our checking account
隐藏在这些话题的才是真正想要讨论的东西.比如我害怕,我感到孤独,我想你了
you get beneath those things to the real statement which is I'm scared or I feel lonely or I miss you right
真正的亲密关系是你愿意涉足到这些令人不安的话题上
these truly intimate connections if you'll just if you'll yeah if you'll just wade into the uncomfortable waters of discourse well
我认为在关系中唯一巩固你的存在就是争执.
我最近经常陷入争执,而我又不是一个喜欢争执的一个人.
但我不喜欢拖延的性格又让我经常陷入争执当中
I and I think the way to fortify yourself in relationship to that I mean I've been embroiled in a lot of conflict and I really don't like conflict and I think the reason that I've been embroiled in so much is because I won't delay it like
如果有一个问题在手上,我愿意立马处理它
if there's an issue at hand I want to address it right now
而我处理问题的原因不是我喜欢处理问题,实际上我一点也不喜欢处理问题
and the reason for that isn't that I enjoy it in fact I don't enjoy it at all
是因为我不喜欢延长争执,因为延长了的争执不会自我处理,不会自我消逝不见
but what I really don't enjoy is prolonged conflict that never goes anywhere and that never ends
延迟的争执到最后只会放大
and so conflict delayed is conflict Amplified exactly
它只会在你身上慢慢变大
just it just grows on you exactly
这是人们一直在口口相传的问题
that and and that's one of the oldest stories that people have been telling each other forever is that
被忽视的事情会在城市外,在黑暗中生长,直到它长到庞然大物,破坏一切
ignored things grow in the darkness outside the city until they become monstrous and Break Down the Walls
然后你说我害怕起争执,我害怕倾听,我害怕听到问题
and so you think well I'm afraid of having I'm afraid of listening I'm afraid of hearing the problems and
这很正常啊.因为这些的确是值得害怕的东西,但它们还没有让你害怕到什么都不做
that's fair enough it's no wonder you're afraid but you're nowhere near afraid enough of not doing that
因为迟早这会导致一个血淋淋的灾难,一个定时炸弹,你把它放个10年,等它响的时候,就是你婚姻的结束的时刻
because that's a bloody catastrophe that'll be a bomb  that'll go off in 10 years and blow up your marriage
你会发现你的妻子早就有了情人,这有她自己的理由.这也因为你在过去的15年之间没有对她付任何的精力
you'll find out that your wife had an affair because well for her own reasons and because you didn't pay any attention to her for like 15 years
然后你说我当初不愿意在这方面付精力.
那看看你现在的境地怎么样.起码你现在的出境比之前来说算不上进步
and then you think well I was afraid to pay attention and yeah fair enough but now look where you are you're you're in hell and and that's just not an improvement
在当今社会里,到底该怎么判断什么时候来涉足.....
and so how do you know in our current ecosystem how do you know when to Wade through uh
我年幼的弟弟给我发了,在2000年 Y2K这个电脑bug会把我们全杀了,在2001年发生啥,具体的我忘了
my little brother sent me something the other day that was like in 2000 Y2K was going to kill us all in 2001 I don't remember what it was like
病毒会在2003年毁灭我们
swine flu is going to kill us all in 2003
狼来了的话语说了太多次了,我已经进入疲惫期了
there's just this Litany of we rally around this the next end thing that's gonna happen and then we've reached this um this fatigue right
现在就是外面有真正的邪恶在朝我们袭来,而我们已经没有精力去处理了,我还是过我的日子吧
and we like there's true cancers out there that are coming for us that we're just like dude I don't have the energy anymore,I'm moving on about my day
我也在想这个问题,我在过去的几个月能尝试给出一些指导方针
I've been really trying to think that through and so here's some guidelines that I've sort of developed over the last few months
在这个世界上,问题的程度有大有小.最大的问题就像你刚才说的那些毁灭性的问题
so you know there's there's problems of various size out there in the world and the largest problems are the apocalyptic problems that you just described right and
而且这些毁灭性的问题的真假也不是显而易见的
it isn't even obvious which of those apocalyptic problems are real
但是我们知道大型复杂系统是总有一天会突然崩溃的
but we could say well there's always the possibility that large-scale systems will come to a precipitous collapse
我们只能接受它.我们的生命也是这样,我们随时都可以死亡,所以多陪伴自己爱的人
and we have to live with that.that's true in our own lives we could die at any moment so look at the people we love
我们文明也可以土崩瓦解,世界末日的恐怖永远都可能发生
like our cultures can fall apart the apocalyptic terror is always beckoning as a possibility
那关键问题是,这是你的问题吗?
okay now the question is is that your problem
John:其实你啥都干不了.P: 这个问题的答案是,你的神经系统会告诉你这个答案
now the answer you do anything about it right the answer is your own nervous system will tell you that
如果你遇到的问题太过巨大,你的神经系统会麻痹你,会让你成为一个暴君
because imagine that you're imagine you're facing a problem that's so big that it paralyzes you and it turns you into a tyrant
然后你就知道这个问题超过你的能力范围
okay that's too big a problem for you obviously
而你要做的就是把问题缩小到到一个你愿意处理的程度
and what you have to do is you have to scale back the problem until you find a dragon that's a size that you're willing to contend with that,you'll actually contend with.
如果你的房子已经是一个血淋淋的灾难的话,也许你不应该涉及大型政治问题
and so you know maybe you shouldn't be addressing the large-scale political problems of the world because your own house is a bloody catastrophe
如果你因为看新闻,而新闻里的内容使你的神经系统麻痹了你,让你变成了一个暴君,也许你不适合干政治
and you watch the news and it paralyzes you and turns you into a ranting Tyrant and that means you're not the man for that job
所以你需要调整你问题的难度.如果你调整了,锻炼了,在本地把事情处理的井井有条,
本地的事情更难.当你干的越来越好,你能处理的问题才越来越大,也才能更实际和有效地处理
you have to scale back and maybe if you scale backed and practiced straightening things up at the local level which are which isn't trivial or easy you get better and better at it and then you could face larger and larger catastrophes and and and practically and productively
而不是在社交媒体上以说自己站在道义的一方,然后在社交媒体上指点江山
instead of virtue signaling and going astray
我在诊所的经常这样干
you know you do this in therapy is
如果有人说自己很难交朋友,你得把这个问题分解成小问题,一步一步来解决
if someone is having a hard time making friends you break that down into micro steps and
有可能你需要教这个人如何自我介绍
one thing you might have to do as we discussed is you might have to teach the person to introduce themselves
所以当有人说自己的问题是没有朋友
you know and their problem is I don't have any friends it's like
不是的,你的问题是你不知道如何握手,然后真诚地看着对方
no no your problem is you don't know how to shake hands and look someone in the eye right
然后你问他,这些你能做到吗?
and then you might say well can you do that
他说自己害怕握手
and they might say well I'm afraid to shake hands
那你能看着我吗?你能把你的手伸出来吗?你能用你的手来碰我的手吗?
it's like well can you look at me?can you stretch out your hand?you know can you touch my hand
我知道这看起来微不足道
I mean this might sound trivial
但很多人都因为社交恐惧而不知道该如何握手
but lots of people are paralyzed with social anxiety and they have no idea how to shake your hands
而这个问题直接让交朋友这个程序没法运行下去了
yeah yeah yeah there and that just stops them cold right
如果连握手都做不到的话,那你怎么能交上朋友呢?
if you can't introduce yourself how the hell are you going to make friends
是的,我们身体会告诉我们一切想知道的
that's right well it's it's being when our bodies take off on u
我喜欢你这个说法
I love how you said that man
我们的神经系统一般都会把真实情况表述出来
because our nervous system tells the truth generally
与其立马去Google,WebMD找出一个答案,
我能不能先想清楚我的身体在保护我自己不受什么的伤害
can I listen to my body and just instead of rushing to the diagnostic and rushing to Google or rushing to a WebMD trying to can I just ask myself what's my body trying to protect me from
我刚走进一个充满人的屋子,我的心跳就升到了200,
我的手心开始出汗了
like what whoa I just walked into a room full of people and my heart rate just went up to 200 beats uh per minute,and I can't my hands are getting sweaty
我的身体到底在防止我受到什么样的伤害
what are you trying to protect me from?
这些是我认识的人,是我朋友,这是一个受到邀请来参加的婚礼.
these are my people these are my friends this is my this is a wedding I got invited to oh okay I
我知道我我以前不怎么适应这样的环境,但现在我是安全的
I used to not be safe in this situation I'm safe now I'm okay now and
如果我能想明白这个区别
那我就不会立马冲到吧台喝酒,或者去零食桌吃蛋糕,来缓解我紧张的情绪了
I can think that through that gap between instead of racing over to the bar to grab a drink to quiet that alarm system or to race over to the snack table and get a piece of cake which is what I go that's quite the alarm system.
我是个南方基督教徒,所以我更喜欢吃来缓解紧张
I'm a good Southern Christian so I like to eat my feelings
当然我并不会这么做,因为我不想面对危险的时候,把我的神经系统给麻痹掉
like I instead of those issues I can just be really curious and I'm not gonna go to war with my body and try to shut the alarms off
我想做的就是听我的身体讲,想它到底想告诉我什么
I'm just going to listen to him and say hey what's it trying to tell me right
你之前提过,我们思考的结果是以图像的形式展示的
now well you you talked about thinking in images before
我要说一个精神分析学家发现的事
so here's a very useful thing the psychoanalysts learn to do
想象你进入到了一个社交场所,你发现你开始紧张和出汗
so imagine you do go to a social occasion and you find as you enter the Hall you you're getting nervous and sweaty
如果你现在观察的话....这也是荣格说"You live life through your drea'm(你在想象中过日子?)"
now if you watch this is why Carl Jung for example believed that we lived through a dream we lived life through a  dream
刚才提到的是一个场景.如果在那个场景里你感到紧张的话,
而且你还特别在意你的紧张的话,你就会在你的大脑里开始胡思乱想了
so and that's a story and so what you'll see is that if you if you feel that nervousness and you attend to it a little drama will run in your head in images
你可能会想,如果我走进去的话,没人会和我说话.
然后这个场景就会在你的大脑中以图片的形式展现出来,然后你还不断的脑补接下来会发生的事情
you know and it'll be something like well I'm going to go in here and no one's going to talk to me and this will happen in pictures like a little movie
没人会跟我说话,我肯定会一个人呆在角落里,我会感到很无聊,
我会出汗发热,我会感到很不舒服.然后上次我参加了个同样的聚会,发生了贼恐怖的事情
no one's going to talk to me and I'm going to end up in the corner and I'm going to be bored and I'm going to be sweaty and hot and it's going to be real uncomfortable and it's just like this other time when I went to this social occasion and this terrible thing happened
你自己把一个连续剧想出来了
and the whole drama will play out in your head
然后你发现了这个连续剧的一个瑕疵
就是其实还是有人可以和你交流的,你们还可以谈谈你脑中想的这个剧情
and then you know you think oh that's  the problem and then well then maybe you have someone to talk to about that fantasy
或者你说,不对啊,这次和上次不一样,我有朋友和我一起参加这个活动
or maybe because now you have the fantasy in front of you and you looked at it you can think well wait a minute as you said wait a minute wait a second,it isn't like that other situation my friends are here
我可以和John说话,我了解他,我们可以好好聊聊
I can go talk to John I know him real well we'll just have a conversation
我可以找个桌子坐下来,和我的朋友在一起度过大部分时间
I can go sit at a table and and with one of my friends and spend most of the time there
我也可以和我妻子呆在一起
it can be with my wife
问题的关键就是,当你开始紧张,你的幻想会自然而然的出现,
而你为了立马逃避它,关闭它,你就会做出不成熟,不理性的答案
but that what will happen is we get nervous and that fantasy will make itself manifest but you don't want to face it and that's when you rush to a premature solution you shut it off right yeah
而你急于做出不成熟的反应,反而让你没法看出自己充满焦虑的幻想到底是什么?
so what what you're doing there is you're failing to allow the anxiety ridden fantasy to make itself manifest
你为什么急于给出一个答案,是因为你不想知道你的脆弱之处是啥
and you you do that because you don't want to know where You're vulnerable right
谁闲得没事干会想知道自己的弱点是啥呢
and no wonder like who the hell wants to know where they're vulnerable
那些想修复自己弱点的人想知道
but the answer to that is well someone who wants to fix
因为不修复的话,你就没法情感上连接
because you cannot connect
我想知道,我现在到了一个阶段,我想知道我的弱点是啥
I do yeah I do absolutely right now now I've come to I love looking for those vulnerabilities
我需要一个好的社区,我需要沟通,我需要指出我不足的朋友
I love a good community and I love the discourse I love my friends who will Point them out
然后这又回到一开始说的,我们需要其它人出现在我们的生活中,来指出我的忽视的地方
um and say hey here's a blind spot which is why again circling back that's why we have to have other people in our life
如果能以正确的心态来....now if done with the in the right spirit I love um I love
这就和做科学研究一样,每次被论文被打回来,都有的修改的建议
并不是内容真的一无是处,只是需要修改才能错的更少
that's that's the whole scientific process right rejecting the note like I wasn't wrong right like the whole idea is Let's Be a little bit less wrong right
说的对,我觉得谦逊的真正意思就是承认自己的不足,愿意让自己错的更少
so I think there's yeah that's right that's the whole idea that's humility man is to be a little bit less wrong
承认自己有不足之处的生活总比事事都要做对的生活更轻松吧
and Jesus that's what it what a deal but what a what a fun way to live it's such an easier way to live than I have to be right
事事都要做对的话,这种生活是不是太累了,太透不过气了.that's a that is an exhausting grip on your life it's a choking grip on your life
我希望我可以少犯一些错误,所以我在寻找自己可以改进的方向.
instead of I want to be a little bit less wrong and I begin to seek out places where I might be wrong
就好比把你的剑刃拿出来,把它磨砺锋刃.这样的生活该多有趣啊
that's just taking your blade and trying to sharpen it as finely as possible.What  a fun way to live.
古典的忏悔也是表达的同样的意思
the old the purpose of confession classically was exactly that
检查自己的薄弱之处,这一点也不是个坏的想法
so the idea was well I'm going to review my weak which doesn't seem like such a bad idea
为什么这不是一个坏的想法呢
Why?
我想知道为什么我上次做的事情为什么没成功.我想看看我能不能总结出原因.
我想知道如果不那么做,还有没有其它办法来得到好一点的结果
即使我没找到,起码我尝试寻找了更好的解决方法
well I'm gonna think about things that I did that didn't work out so well and see if I can specify what they were and see if I can figure out how to replace them with something better at least with the intent to do
better
原则上来说,教堂内的忏悔是在某种程度上带有赎罪性质的,
希望通过阐明自己的错误才期许宽恕
and that confessional you know that confessional in some sense which was supposed to be Redemptive and that led to forgiveness
但忏悔的作用其实和在日常对话中讨论生活的问题相差无二.
was very much the same thing as discussing in genuine dialogue the problems of your life
这周我好像走上邪路了
it's like well here I seem to have gone sideways here I seem to have gone sideways here this week
我是怎么知道我走上邪路了?
how do I know that well
我的良心告诉我的
my conscience is calling me out on it and
一些可怕的时候发生了,我觉得它们的存在是个错误.我不想再犯同样的错误了\
and there were some negative consequences and I feel that this is the mistake I made and I'd rather not make that mistake
如果你想把问题解决话,如果你的目标是逐步停止犯这些错误,
也许这些错误的出现就是正向改变的起始.
and as you said if that's handled as if the goal is to stop making those mistakes hopefully incrementally across time then the evidence of the mistake can be an invitation to positive transformation
谦虚会鼓励你去做这些改变
and that would be the encouraging element of humility
那我们为什么还没.....(打断施法)
right it's like well why haven't we
我觉得你只有在集体内才能做到
but you have to do it in community
我觉得这个的起源于古老宗教的忏悔
I think I think the like it went from this ancient religious practice of confession
当你回首看,这种行为已经在文化层面上发展了上千年了,因为这个行为真的有其内在价值
which I think you have to look back thousands of years and say this practice this practice continued to roll on evolutionarily and culturally,because it had a deep value and then
我觉得现代的互助小组这种形式,在其它人面前阐述自己的问题,
很好的吸收这种忏悔的内在价值
it was I don't say co-opt it was by the Mental Health Community to sit down in front across from somebody and
对我来说,写作也有同样的效果.把自身的感受带出我的身体,写在纸上
I find great great value in journaling writing things down getting them out of my body and onto paper
但我觉得我这个写作舒展自身的问题就是,
我只是在对自己忏悔,这个行为本身是孤立的,没有影响到外界.当然我这个行为本身就有一定的价值
but I think we've gotten very isolated with our journaling and are writing it down and we've become um I'm having this confession with myself now,and there's value to that
但是我觉得这个行为在集体中才能有更大的价值.
因为这样才能得到"当你知道我的一切的时候,你还能向以前一样陪伴我,爱我吗"的答案?
but I think the truth value is having confession in front of somebody else because then we force ourselves to say do you see me and do you still love me will you still be here if you fully know me that
我觉得观察自身的最大的缺陷就是人永远看不到自己看不见的地方.
你当然可以通过写作,通过观察自身,但有可能你看不见的地方你依然看不见
it's the most difficult part of yourself to observe is the place where you're most blind obviously and so you can journal and you can concentrate on yourself but that still might produce a situation where your blindest spots stay blind and
而这也限制了你解决问题的方式,因为你只能使用自己的资源
also it limits your ability to problem solve creatively because you only draw on your own resources
而正常运转的婚姻的一个好处就是,但任何事情发生的时候,你们有两个大脑来思考
one of the wonderful things about a marriage that's functional is that both of you have two brains to work on to work out whatever problem happens to arise
而婚姻生活难熬的有一部分原因就是,生活本身就很难熬.
而婚姻要求你们一起面对生活中真实存在问题.这也是婚姻不同于约会的理由
and part of the reason that marriage is difficult is because life is difficult and you you have to jointly confront the actual problems of life which is what makes marriage different different than dating
婚姻和出轨不同的在于,出轨是一种充满美好,没有任何问题的幻想.
for example or different than an affair which is a you know a wish a wish fulfillment fantasy in some sense of all the intimacy with none of the problems
这是个对你伴侣很糟糕的行为,因为你把问题都留给了他
a very terrible thing to do to your partner who is then laden with only the problems
两个人思考的好处也是不言而喻的.因为每个人都是不同,
和你沟通的那个人,有与你对问题和答案的不同理解的概率可是不低的
but it's very useful to have two brains because each person is quite different and the probability that the person you're communicating with will have a different take on both the problem and the solution is extremely high
特别是,当你正在陷入和你精神健康有关系的自我认知的危机中
and so this is particularly true if you're in a solipsistic uh crisis in relationship to your mental health
当你抑郁的时候,你是很难独自走出抑郁的.
因为你身上的某些问题在加重你的抑郁程度
for example if you're depressed it's very hard to lift yourself out of that alone because some of that dwelling on your issues actually facilitates the depression
焦虑同理
and the same thing happens with anxiety
现在我们集聚在这,你是一个高度训练的临床心理医生,我是一个受到训练的咨询师.
如果你们不在学术圈的话,我想说一句,我们在能力上有阶级的区别
so now that we're here you're you're a trained in practice clinical psychologist I'm a trained I'm a lowly trained counselor which for the non-academics there's a there's a definite hierarchy there
我们是不是把我们的文化,我们个体太过病态化了
have we over pathologized culture our individuals are
我觉得我们已经成为"诊断标签"的盲从的依附者
i feel like we have become um a slavish adherence to Diagnostics into labeling and
当我看到"预期理论"把人们分成一个个的类型
,每个类型的人都有别人期待他们干的事情
when I look at when I look at expectation theories that people live into the labels that they're given or the expectations that are put before them
我对这种理论有些忧虑,但我不想太过轻率,所以我想问问你的答案
I've got some high concern ,but I also don't want to be dismissive right so help me with that
我觉得现在人太容易就能得到了一个诊断标签了.然后他们就把那个诊断标签的定义当成了他自己
because I feel like everybody man it's so easy to just go get a diagnostic and go get a label and that becomes you
然后我得和一个人坐到一起,听他说我不适合这个工作
,因为他自称他被诊断为了ADHD或者被诊断为了社会恐惧症
and then I end up sitting with somebody and they say well I can't take this job because I was diagnosed with ADHD or I was diagnosed with social anxiety disorder
我想说,那是一个背景介绍不是一个理由,
它只是告诉你,你看世界,和其它人看你的一种方式
and my impulse  is hey that's a context not an excuse,it is a way a way that you see and experience the world and people experience you and
你依然要和正常人一样去工作
you still got to get up and go to work
我们该如何处理这种情况呢?我想听你的说话
so how are we going to manage that  right but I I don't want to be dismissive well
我觉得这个问题很难说的原因就是,
这是个真实存在的问题,而我们又需要诊断标签的结果来决策一些事情,比如报保险
look I think part of the problem is is that it's a practical problem in some sense because the diagnostic labeling process is necessary for such things as insurance claims right and
Jordan:诊断标签里里面的词语.....
John:这是这个存在的原因吗,这也太可悲了吧
Jordan: 它还是有它的可取之处的
so so the the the Lexicon is that is that where we are man of course it is and the Lexicon it's heartbreaking
man well and there's some utility in it
当你有了一次惊恐发作后,你就害怕走出家门了.
我可以确定的告诉你,你有了广场恐惧症,而且不止你得过
.you know if if you're having panic attacks and you're afraid to go out of your house and I tell you you have agoraphobia and many other people have
这类消息有时候能起到舒心的作用,
因为你并不是这个世界里唯一一个受这种情况影响的人
it sometimes that's a real relief because you're not the only crazy person of that type in the world
而且存在一些手段来治愈它
and there's some pathway to treatment
我是以一个行为学家的身份来被训练的.
而行为学家对你说的诊断标签这个理论并不怎么感冒
but I was trained fundamentally as a behaviorist and the behaviorists aren't that uh what would you call it impressed with diagnostic labels
理由是,他们更喜欢把问题分成更细小,但能区分开来的单位
and the reason for that is that they tend to break down problems into actionable units
所以当你说你抑郁了之后,他们更想知道,在极为细节的程度上
,你的生活你的状态,发生了什么样的改变.
然后才是,该如果一对一的解决这些问题
it's like well I'm depressed it's like well okay fair enough but what's wrong with your life and your mood in the micro details and how could we address that programmatically and
而我觉得诊断的问题在于,你很容易把诊断的结果
和病症(导致这个诊断结果的原因)混在一起
I think the problem with diagnosis is that it's really easy to confuse diagnosis with cause
我现在很痛苦.为什么?因为我有抑郁症.
right but I'm miserable why well because I'm depressed
也许你有生物化学分泌的问题,但除此之外,抑郁并不是让你把任何同质的东西放进去的黑箱
now well maybe you have a biochemical problem but absent that depression isn't an a black box with homogeneous contents
一定有导致你痛苦和不开心的理由
there's specific reasons that you're miserable and unhappy and
而我们要做的就是把这些理由区别开来.
然后更加细分这些理由,直到我们可以开始尝试解决他们
what we need to do is to break down those reasons differentiate them down to the level of detail where you can start to experiment with addressing them
而当诊断公司涉及进来的时候,他们起到了干扰的作用.
我们经常能看这种干扰,是起反作用的.
and so if the diagnostic Enterprise interferes with that then it's counterproductive and and that happens very frequently
我还记得我第一次看见我的学生因为重度抑郁和自杀想法而进了医院.
yeah I remember the first time one of my students was hospitalized for major depression and suicidal ideation
在他们得到休息和吃食几天后,我对接下来发生的事情很震惊
I was taken aback that the first couple of days after you know they had gotten sleep and were fed
指南上说,你的任务就是,起来,洗个澡,然后回到床上去
the protocol was your job is to get up and go take a shower and then you can go back to bed
我们每次只要做这些小步骤就行了
we're going to take these tiny steps towards right
Dave Ramsey(John的老板,他们是债务偿还公司)说:
我们要得到1000美元,我不管你要卖什么东西.
只要能拿到1000美元,你可以把你最好的吉他给卖掉.然后把这钱存在到储蓄卡里
that's you know my friend Dave Ramsey is okay we're gonna get a thousand dollars sell whatever you got sell your famous guitar sell your gonna get a thousand dollars in a savings account first and
你就可以先长舒一口气了.因为我们知道,
我们迟早会帮你把你的负债偿还清楚的
you're gonna breathe for the first time and then we're going to pay off your debt and then we're good
正是这样的一小步,我们才能朝.....(付清债务?)
right it's these tiny baby steps towards
长久以来我们被灌输,精神健康就对事务有正确的认知
um and again I think we've been sold a bill of goods that mental health is  I just got to get all the thought right thoughts in the right order and I
好像我们好像放弃了行为学知识
there's something I think we just swiped off wholesale the behaviorist approach
我只是认为单纯认知正确并不有效
I I just don't see that working out man
我认为我们得行动起来,只有行动起来我们才能以一种的不同方式思考和经历这个世界
I think we have to often act our way into a different way of thinking and experiencing the world
还有一点重要的是,人们需要对结果有信心,
要振作起来.我们之前在级联效应也提到过这点
well the other thing too that people should take heart in consequence of is that as you pointed out earlier when we were talking about the cascading effects
还是以和你的家人吃完饭为例
let's say of sorting out how you have dinner with your family
在这个问题上,有乘积效应(大概就是每天你多努力一点,100天后,你比你100天前强了1.1^100倍)的体现.
there's multiplying effects
一开始是很很难看到你进步的成效的
well it might be very disheartening to see at what small scale you have to begin improvements
但事实就是,当你开始提升了,你进步的程度会指数级的增长
right but the truth of the matter is is that that tends to scale exponentially is once you start making improvements
进步会反过来作用于其它进步
the improvements feed back upon themselves and
即使你一开始只是向上迈了一小步.不久之后,你就会发现的你趋势是往上的
so even if you have to start out small it doesn't take very long before you're on the upward trajectory and
然后你还不是线性上升
it's not linear you know
你可以瞬间失败,你也可以瞬间成功,只要你开始行动的话
you can fail precipitously right but you can also succeed precipitously once you get the ball rolling
正向的事务往往会聚集在一起
positive things tend to aggregate together
你可以进步巨大即使你从一个糟糕的起点出发
and you can make a lot of progress even if you start from a pretty damn dismal place
那么我们该如何把这种非凡的想法传播给大众呢?
so how do we get that that extraordinary insight into the public lexicon
该如何让这种想法成为世界运行的规律呢?
how does that become a way of operating
因为现在大家都过于关注自我,
不在意别人的看法,只期待自己不要犯错误
because all of us are staring we're running around staring at our own belly buttons,waiting to not fall off that precipitous Decline and
我们正在错失创伤后加速成长的机会
we are missing the opportunity for this accelerating post-traumatic growth
当我们经历了一些难受的事情,我们现在要做什么,我们接下来来要做什么?
right we've been through hard things,that's the whole book man well what do we now what do we do next
如何把这个想法带到公共区域?答案就是,
that's the answer to your question well how do we bring that into the public domain
你写了一本书,你参加了这场对话,这是你的方法
well you wrote a book having this conversation and so yeah and  and that is how you do it
你还尝试传播在你这个
谦虚勇敢的渐进式前进运动,诚信沟通,社会共同体
,以及我们今天讨论的一切,的有用性
and and you try to communicate the utility of what would you call it humble courageous incremental movement forward and honest communication social Community all the things that we discussed today and
我们在youtube上的时间已经不多了
I should also point out that we are out of time for the YouTube all right interview
你还有其他事情想跟电视机前的观众说的吗?
is there anything else that you want to bring to the attention of the people who are watching and listening before we before we close
我只想说感谢你的招待,感谢这次机会,我谢谢你
no I just want to say I'm I'm grateful for your hospitality it's been you've been a gift I appreciate you well thank
也谢谢你,谢谢你的书,对现在在看和听的观众,我想对你说
and thank you for your book and I would say to people who are watching and listening
Deloney博士的书是一本直截了当,
告诉你如何用实际有用的方法渐进式的改善你生活的一本书
Dr delony's book is a very straightforward take on practical solutions that you can Implement to start incrementally improving your life
这就是进步的正确方法
每次一块砖,你就能建立坚固的城墙
and that is the right way to to progress one brick at a time you build a solid wall one brick at a time
进步会比你想的更快发生
and it can happen a lot faster than you think
我觉得这本书填补一个很重要的空缺
and so I think the book fills a necessary Niche and
我喜欢哭诉者这一章,你在这一章里交叉叙述了你对经历
,自我认知,广泛的社会群体的理解和渐进式提升的议题
I like the whiner in which you interwove your description of story and identity and the broader social community and the issue of incremental Improvement and so
我鼓励大家去读一读
I'd encourage people thank you for watching and listening to take a look
我也很开心有这次机会和你聊一聊
yeah yeah and it was real good talking to you
我们要去另一个平台,daily wire plus,再去聊半个小时的了
for those of you who are watching and listening I'm going to talk to Dr eloney for another half an hour on the daily wire plus platform
这个平台让我们有机会在youtube上创造这样
的对话视频,所以感谢他们吧
daily wire plus platform and the daily wire plus makes these professionally produced YouTube conversations possible,and so thank you to them for that
如果你想听到更过关于Delony博士的事情,
他如何成功的,他的婚姻,请跳到另一个平台聆听吧
and if you're interested in hearing a little bit more about Dr delony's biography and about what's made him successful in his career and his marriage then head on over to the Daily wire plus platform and and tune in
如果你不感兴趣的话,希望下次还能在我的youtube
频道看到你.感谢你投入时间听我讲
otherwise hopefully we'll see all of you again on my YouTube channel and thank you very much for your time and attention
关注鹰酱喵,关注鹰酱谢谢喵